[{"id":"recWqw0tDxDtthVtm","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I dispose of my recycling in Tulsa? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Answer":"The City of Tulsa offers curbside recycling for many common recyclables on regular trash days. If you live in a building that doesn't offer recycling bins, or can't access curbside recycling for another reason, there are three recycling centers where you can drop it off: 3495 S. Sheridan Rd in Central Tulsa, 1101 S. Cincinnati Ave. in Downtown, and 2160 Garnett Rd at Plaza Santa Cecilia in East Tulsa. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","reck1kwu0Ax8s2U3s","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recZGgJu72BM3szBu"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recYxyozUofEDYmrt","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I apply for a building, electrical or fire permit from the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"Tulsa operates an online self-service portal where property owners can search for, apply, and track the progress of 160 different types of permits. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recmjTVmhqoXN6Y2o","recfjJwBURwqfGO8D","recAtWXbEzVaD72ND","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recZekbRTdqP7GLre","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I activate utility service at my new residence in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Answer":"Activating utility service can be as simple as sending an email to [tulsa311@cityoftulsa.org](mailto:tulsa311@cityoftulsa.org) or making a call to Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center. You could also visit the Utilities Customer Service Office at City Hall during busines shours. If you're calling or visiting in person, be prepared to provide your: name, telephone number, social security number, and address for service. If you activate via e-mail, provide all that information except for SSN, a Customer Care representative will follow up via phone to collect it. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","rec754rVxMJQaT6iC","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recZrqUgzNK95KbGi","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Can I pay a traffic or parking ticket online in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["traffic & parking tickets"],"Answer":"**Yes.** But it depends on the ticket. If the ticket you receive doesn't display a dollar amount for your fine in large font, but instead has the word \"COURT\" printed near the top, you cannot pay online and must appear in court. If your ticket does have a dollar amount, regardless of the amount, you can pay online through this web page. Be aware: tickets take 7-10 days to post online, if you try to pay before then you may not find it so it's worth checking back later. You can also use the system to pay fines for certain criminal code violations.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVswcqhjkahPslp","rectD3gKNXIFdjHUQ","recbDMq2PvDBET39y","recgEFDA1BHBx8LRL","recCqZ0iIe1Qu9MWz","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"rectHaqVPSkDxULn8","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build a detached shed or garage on my property? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential accessory structure permit. The permit is required for any detached structure on the same parcel of property as a principal structure (house) and the use of which is incidental (related to, in support of) the principal structure. You can apply for such a permit here \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recmjTVmhqoXN6Y2o","recI5o1ZfuGhyBI3f","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recuvoyP7aTEcrWRF","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build an outdoor storm shelter on my property?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential outdoor storm shelter permit. Be aware: you should only apply for this permit if the shelter you intend to install a shelter that meets FEMA or ICC standards. Plans must be sealed bu an Oklahoma registered engineer or bear a valid and current FEMA certification. You can apply for a permit through Tulsa's self service portal.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recuAGwtc736aGtNn","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build a pool on my property?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You need a permit for both above-ground and in-ground pools. You can apply for one through Tulsa's permit self service portal. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recETZKzvZIxk74ml","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recy2kKsEtjXqj2yd","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to improve the drainage on my property or change its grade?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"You may need a residential watershed permit to move earth on your property for activities such as: excavating, grading, regrading, land filling, land clearing, etc. You can apply for a permit through Tulsa's self service portal. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recQqqKXV7tZV5TZh","recI5o1ZfuGhyBI3f"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recCHaTr7GPnNqXc4","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build a retaining wall on my property?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential retaining wall permit. Be aware: you'll need an engineer's seal on your plans for them to be approved. You can apply for a permit through Tulsa's self service portal.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recOq5l1PZm4vQCyk","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recEojYIYnlBCKvxJ","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What kind of records are considered public in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["public records"],"Answer":"Management of public records in Tulsa and all other municipalities in the state is governed by Oklahoma's Open Records Act. That law, similar to other states, considers the overwhelming majority of government records as public by default. Generally speaking, the only records produced by, or in the custody of, government agencies/departments that are exempt from public disclosure are those which contain private medical information, information about children, or certain personal information about public employees (such as their home address or disciplinary investigations on their record).  \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","reced3M3XwUKN3vYM","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recFi3e8eDF2OSp9B","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How can I find out if I live in a part of Tulsa with a neighborhood association? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Answer":"If you just moved in to an area with a neighborhood association, there's a chance that an association member will try to reach out to invite you to join. If you don't hear anything or you've lived at your residence for a while and are curious, Tulsa has an online map showing each registered association, its boundaries, and contact information. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recQab7UGmkPuTB5O","recoJacT6bxOqTcxz","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recG6HLRAg8ji5ImW","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to have storm shelter installed inside of my residence?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential indoor storm shelter permit. Be aware: you should only apply for this permit if the shelter you intend to install a shelter that meets FEMA or ICC standards. Plans must be sealed bu an Oklahoma registered engineer or bear a valid and current FEMA certification. You can apply for a permit through Tulsa's self service portal.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec8t9nmRIbtvxP1x"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recLmK4VpaNtFVKvV","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Can I pay my City of Tulsa utility bill online?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Answer":"The City of Tulsa offers a self-service portal where residents can pay their utility bills and find information about their meter readings. You'll need your customer ID and Customer account number to setup your online account. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recCqZ0iIe1Qu9MWz","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recLdVK9I3LfGlAbo","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I shut-off or transfer my utility service to a new address?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Answer":"If you are listed on the utility account, you can shut off or transfer service by emailing [tulsa311@cityoftulsa.org](mailto:tulsa311@cityoftulsa.org) or calling 3-1-1. You can also visit the Utilities Customer Service Office at City Hall during business hours. You'll need to provide your customer ID and Customer account number. For shut offs, you'll need to provide a a forwarding address for the final bill (if applicable). After submitting a request, it usually takes 3 business days to transfer service or shut it off. For shut-offs, any outstanding balance will be charged against any deposit, then a final bill will be sent to you. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","rec754rVxMJQaT6iC","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recLJB4zNZyKJov59","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to hold a wedding or other large gathering at my residence?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"You may need a permit for a special assembly if you're holding a special event such as a holiday party, wedding reception, or hosting entertainment at a facility not designated for assembly (such as your house). If you need a special assembly permit, you may need a special event permit as well. Consider contacting the Tulsa Fire Department or Tulsa 3-1-1 for help determining whether your gathering requires a permit and which ones to apply for. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","rec65mwzeCqZrmncE","recZoil9936fwmqaL","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"rec0l9LFxEcUDNj2G","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I register my storm shelter with the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["register stuff"],"Answer":"If you live within the city limits, and your storm shelter or safe room meets FEMA and /or ICC building standards, you can register your shelter with the city so First Responders know where to find you in case of a natural disaster. Add your information to the Tulsa Storm Shelter Registry at this webpage\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec8t9nmRIbtvxP1x","recAcDhrN7CzL5Cue","recSlLVBIMDqqcsOz","recEZ7OOZ3hy6PH24"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec0FbPnpWxYbPSyv","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I submit a request for Open Public Records from the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["public records"],"Answer":"A request for Open Public Records must be made in writing. Citizens can do this themselves with a specific form provided by the City. The form is straightforward, but it helps to do some research beforehand about what information you need and what department/agency has the record. Your success in obtaining public records depends largely on how specific you are in describing the information you need. Ideally, you can tell the records custodian the exact name of the document, database, report etc. that you need information from. If not, the custodian is still legally obligated to make a good faith effort to produce the records you request. Once you've completed the form, use information on this page to find the relevant records custodian and submit the form either in-person or via e-mail. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","reced3M3XwUKN3vYM","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec1hJM0z7sHFxMAX","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I opt out of paying Tulsa EMS Authority fees?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["opting out"],"Answer":"You can choose to opt-out your household from Tulsa EMSA online. You'll need to login to your utility account here or register an account if you don't have one. Tulsa's 3-1-1 Customer Care Center can help you through the process if you have questions. Be aware that opting-out means you'll have to pay for EMS out-of-pocket if you or somebody in your household needs assistance. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recoJSpwBlG6Tx4G3","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"rec1EAnNPRpA7bLa3","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Who can I contact if I'm concerned about a tree damaging power lines near my residence?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["report or request"],"Answer":"According to the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit, \n> If you are concerned about trees on your property that are close to overhead utilities, call PSO’s Forestry Infoline at 1-877-367-6815. If needed, they will send a forester to you to determine if trimming or removal is best. If the best option is to remove the tree, PSO often provide vouchers you can use to receive a discount on the purchase of replacement trees and shrubs at participating local nurseries.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","rec6DzgUgFNoHl6AH","recWxmWWRzxnMHenv","recdZj59grW6AoCkH","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"rec3GdEUIDmHwSBfS","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to remodel my kitchen or bathroom?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential alteration permit. Such permits are required for any changes to an existing structure which don't increase the floor area. You can apply for one through Tulsa's permit self service portal online. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"rec5rz5PiayKqG53s","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I obtain public records from the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["public records"],"Answer":"Information about requesting public records from the City of Tulsa is available on the City Finance Department's webpage. There you can download a request form, learn about what records are considered public, find contact information for the custodian of those particular records, and find out how much it may cost to obtain those records. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","reced3M3XwUKN3vYM","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec8hwMCqZbVhtirp","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I schedule a time for the City of Tulsa to pick up my bulky waste?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Answer":"You can schedule a pick-up for bulky waste by calling 918-596-9777 or through your online utilities account. Go here to login or register your account. You'll need your customer ID number, account number, and your SSN. Bulky waste pick-up costs $10 per 8 cubic feet. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"rec8xRk3pQw0auRa8","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa","voting & elections"],"Question":"How can I find which Tulsa City Council District I live in?","Tags":["accessing tulsa","voting & elections"],"Concepts":["maps"],"Answer":"Visit Tulsa's online district map [here](https://cityoftulsa.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=5ee4acc23016404aae82bc8100168a4c). \n\nWith this map, you can enter a specific address to see which of Tulsa's 9 Council Districts it falls into. Searching an address or clicking on the map will also provide a link to information about that District as well as contact information for the City Councilor who represents it. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec7CRt7SqLSMHpq0","recqcNghusgnZYF1X","recNk1hJFap0wM73G","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rechyIcFk8RqZkDx8","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build a deck on my property?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"\n**Yes.** You'll need a residential deck permit. You can apply for one through Tulsa's permit self service portal. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"rechB3tyvdB14vB3f","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What occupations are licensed by the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Concepts":["licenses"],"Answer":"You need a license from the City to legally work in most contractor roles, including the following:\n\n- Electrical\n- Residential electrical\n- Electrical with security alarm\n- General contractor\n- Mechanical\n- Plumbing.\n\nAdditionally, licenses are required to work on fire alarm and sprinkler and suppression systems. Fire suppression system installation businesses also must hold a business license. \n\nOccupational license applications are available on Tulsa's [self service portal](https://tulsaok-energovweb.tylerhost.net/apps/selfservice#/home). \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recd5Eg4UNwMH4CFQ","recgVOta2Pkb0k7NP","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recT56q21gskzFrmD","recAtWXbEzVaD72ND","recQqTtEpxpp6AbHy"]},{"id":"reciIzpjhVeUJjFHP","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build an addition onto my home?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential addition permit. You can apply for one through Tulsa's permit self-service portal. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","reckEjpC9UPsBgbnF","recIuuMLg0ka4tV4b","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recl9bAOW2diBS2EB","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I know what day to put out my trash for collection in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Answer":"Your weekly collection day depends on your neighborhood. Tulsa offers a map to help you  determine your collection day. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","reck1kwu0Ax8s2U3s","recq4v6FtV3eR1DZe"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"reclwDtRstU3qHBnu","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How can I volunteer my time or skills to help others in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["volunteer"],"Answer":"The City of Tulsa maintains a list of volunteer opportunities with both local organizations and larger ones that benefit Tulsans. You can find out about the organization, the help they need, when/how often they need it, and whether your skills could benefit others through the role. Find out more here. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","reciadpYORsfn5Qbg","recTBiVxKt5P8D7B4","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"]},{"id":"recniWCBkP8PRsMu9","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I have to pay to obtain public records from the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["public records"],"Answer":"Sometimes, depending on what kind of records you request, how many you request, and what you need them for. The city's full fee schedule for public records is here. According to Oklahoma's Open Records Act, government bodies should charge citizens only for the direct cost of producing the record. Paper copies cost $0.25 per sheet, Certified Copies cost $1 per sheet, etc. However, if records are requested for commercial purposes, or if the quantity of records requested is such that producing them will disrupt the essential functions of the government body, the City of Tulsa charges $30/hour. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recQZe9wGJYchUmSF","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recrhc9ForZ6fHB3W"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recn0Od7TdioxlCNb","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Do I need a permit from the City of Tulsa to build a fence or wall on my property?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["permits"],"Answer":"**Yes.** You'll need a residential fence or wall fence permit. Be aware: this permit is not intended for a retaining wall, which requires a separate permit. If you intend to build a masonry wall fence over four feet tall, you'll also need to get plan approval from an engineer. To apply for a permit, visit Tulsa's self service portal. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec1Od7vtYRXy79YZ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recmjTVmhqoXN6Y2o","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recocZNwmoAtpvzGA","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Where can I bring all my recyclable materials that aren't accepted in Tulsa's blue curbside recycling bins?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Answer":"The Metropolitan Environmental Trust (M.e.t.) operates free drop-off recycling centers throughout the metro area, including three in Tulsa. Many of these locations accept items not collected in your blue curbside recycling bin, including plastic bags, motor oil, cooking oil, antifreeze, batteries, electronic waste, and eyeglasses. Visit metrecycle.com for a full list of items and hours. \naccepted at each location\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","recchqDApy3QBKYYZ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recppFWF7pFbf4qUq","recwVwtuJ9JH8GyXW","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recTHQ7p2ei0oiMs2","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much tax money goes into the Tulsa Zoo?","Tags":["public finance"],"Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 City of Tulsa budget allocates **$6,772,000** to manage the Tulsa Zoo. The City plans to spend **$6,942,000** in FY24.\n\nWhile the zoo grounds and its physical structures are owned by the city of Tulsa\n\nTHE ZOO GROUNDS AND PHYSICAL STRUCTURES ARE OWNED BY THE\nCITY OF TULSA. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recVZIpe6J2A9iDQO"],"Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 30._\n\n\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec4GLmcNexViKGz8","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What is Tulsa 311?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Concepts":["report or request"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa 311 is a hotline and online portal for citizens to **report non-emergency issues** and **request city services**. Residents can call by dialing 311, visit the website at [tulsa311.com](http://tulsa311.com), or use the [Tulsa 311 mobile app](https://apps.apple.com/us/app/tulsa-311/id1453372535).\n### Report & Request Forms\n- [Abandoned, Disabled, or Illegally Parked Vehicles](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000261)\n- [Advertising Sign Violations](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000258)\n- [Barking Dog (Noise Complaint)](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000050)\n- [Broken Parking Meter](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000253)\n- [Dead Animal Pickup](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000200)\n- [Dumping Violations](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000263)\n- [Expressway / Decorative Lights Out](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000301)\n- [File a Police Report](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000260)\n- [Flood Plain Inquiry](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000450)\n- [Human Rights Complaint Intake Form](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000300)\n- [Loose Animal](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000256)\n- [Missed Trash Collection](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000400)\n- [New Traffic Sign or Signal Request](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000302)\n- [Pothole](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000001)\n- [Property Violation](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000254)\n- [Sewer Line Break Overflow](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000252)\n- [Street Marker/Street Sign Down](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000257)\n- [Streetlight Maintenance](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000600)\n- [Tort Claim Form](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000262)\n- [Traffic Signal Malfunction](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000255)\n- [Water Line Breaks](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000259)\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["rec797k3CYC8F5O3f"],"Author":"Abby","QA Code":"Abby_Tulsa311_01","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Tulsa 311_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recdHriMxUy8wNHSe","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I report an abandoned or illegally parked car in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["report or request"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center has an online form available [here](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000261) for citizens to reports cars parked illegally or which appear abandoned. Providing the exact address provides the greatest chance of action being taken. If Tulsa authorities confirm a report, the car will be tagged for towing. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec797k3CYC8F5O3f","rec5EtmXDFLl7QB0k","rectD3gKNXIFdjHUQ","recRJBtqeF69Iewhi","recGkXnNzl0pw1ued"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_000","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Tulsa 311_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recwvXEbnPiXOjfwd","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does the City of Tulsa plan on spending in FY23?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The total budget is **$944.9 million,** an increase of $145.5 million (18.2%) over the prior year's budget. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_001","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 7, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recmyE16g9s0Y7bL7","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does the FY23 budget dedicate to day-to-day operations?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The operating budget is **$824 million**, an increase of $113.5 million (16%) over the prior year's operating budget\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recvcH6UgexrbXmq9"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_002","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 7, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recEtHM63ySpYObMK","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does Tulsa plan to spend on improvements to its property and services in FY23? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa funds improvements through its capital budget. Fiscal year 2022-2023 capital budget is **$120.4 million**. Capital funding increased by $32 million (36.2%) over the prior year's budget. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","recI2ycsxZZO6fcFB"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_003","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 7, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rect4UJDtYrQpAPVq","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What economic conditions were present during the process of crafting Tulsa's FY23 budget?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation highlights several economic conditions that may have informed the budget process. Among these are the following.\n\n- **High inflation**: For example, average price of household necessities rose 8.3% in April 2022.\n- **Increased energy costs and slowing investment**: This is thought to be attributed to unfavorable federal policy and/or major employers in the region. Notably, this refers to oil and gas companies.\n- **Developments in Aerospace: **Major employers in the Tulsa metro area have promised to increase investment and employment to support infrastructure at the Tulsa airport.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recRkoks26UJNYZaf","recByHjpLaWIKK5Fj","recvYIjo7YASgdmQQ","rec3JBXzS340jufUz"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_004","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 7-9, Paragraph 3-4, 1-6, 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recVzsAuskELT9vTv","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What were some of the City of Tulsa's priorities in the FY23 budget? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa's priorities for the FY23 budget, in no particular order, include the following. \n\n- Funding **recruitment** efforts to fill vacant positions. Notably, this concerns increasing salary/wage compensation.\n- Improving **customer service** through technology and \"a 27% increase in customer care agents taking citizen calls...about utility bills and other issues\".\n- Increasing **public safety** through focused recruitment efforts at police and fire academies, allocating public safety grant funding, and implementing a Real-time information center (RTIC) to streamline law enforcement intelligence through community surveillance. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recmI8jq7aDVIZwPI","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recVswcqhjkahPslp"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_005","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 9-10, Paragraph 3-5, 1-6_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recVARJku4wgm25qW","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"From where does Tulsa receive the majority of revenue used to fund its operations? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Sales and use taxes account for 63.9% of the General Fund, which is the principal operating fund of the City. General fund revenues for FY2023 are expected to be $358.3 million.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recs5w170YqWhk0EG"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_006","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 11, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recVDotgYTkV1wUlr","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does Tulsa have put aside in case of serious economic downturn or disaster? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa's primary two reserve funds are the General Fund Emergency Operating Reserve, with a balance of **$29.9 million**, and the City's Economic Stabilization Reserve (aka Rainy Day Fund), with an expected balance of **$12.4 million **by the end of FY23. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recZKGlSopefYlgJl","recSlLVBIMDqqcsOz","recqrrvxCjfwfD3Gi","rechtfnL0L7SQWySq"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_007","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 11, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recVE4ypLjJRwI7Ew","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is the largest expenditure for Tulsa's General (day-to-day) Fund? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The largest expenditure category is **payroll**, which represents 70.1% of the General Fund.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec8AeklhglYBxGE1","recvcH6UgexrbXmq9","recs5w170YqWhk0EG"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_008","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 11, Paragraph 6_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recX6GBwnVbuEcwjF","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Where does the City of Tulsa allocate the most significant resources? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Public safety receives the largest allocation of resources at 53.2% of the General Fund. Public Safety includes the following organizations.\n\n- Police Department\n- Fire Department\n- EMS\n- 911 call center\n- Prosecutor's Office. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recyjD9HkhKp1tczB","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_009","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 11, Paragraph 7_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recXzv8UzyocZ8S2I","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"As a Tulsa Metropolitan Utility Authority (TMUA) ratepayer, will I have to pay more for water utility service in FY23? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No.** Resulting from the success of an asset management program, the TMUA did not recommend increases to water rates for FY23. \n\n_Current Rates_\nThe current rate equals $4.31 per 1,000 gallons of water used. \n\n_FY24 Recommendations_\nThe TMUA is recommending a 3% increase for FY24, partially due to increases in chemical costs.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recWdnRM6FA93ACEx","reccm8jum85mxl4b2","recXrn5bEAziLS5hi","recGGzf4fV3y01tu7","recQ4YQuzC7U20psh","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_010","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 12, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recY5PDHpQvqWo1hb","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"As a Tulsa Metropolitan Utility Authority (TMUA) ratepayer, will I have to pay more for sewage treatment utility service in FY23?  ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** A 7% rate increase (from $9.36 to $10.02 per 1,000 gallons of water used per single-family home) is proposed for the sanitary sewer system in FY23.  According to the FY23 budget presentation, debt and scheduled capital improvement projects (together representing nearly half the system's operating budget) are the main drivers of rate increases.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recC80WE0BC0GjA20","recGGzf4fV3y01tu7","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","recXrn5bEAziLS5hi","recQ4YQuzC7U20psh","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_011","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 12, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recYKRQl6QTy2jnt7","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Are rates to maintain the City of Tulsa stormwater management system increasing in FY23? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** Rates are increasing by 8.5% (from $9.03 to 9.80 per month per residential customer). This rate increase is higher than the 7% increase that was originally proposed for FY23. Budget documents attribute the higher increase to the need for additional capital to fund improvement projects identified as high priority via strategic planning study. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recXIehUTkifUvxMa","recQqqKXV7tZV5TZh","recP4EVMzwQakaDpC","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_012","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 12, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec0imwsl4AdFgWkX","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Are rates for trash collection set to increase in FY23? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Possibly. **According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \n> There are currently no changes to rates for trash service in FY23. However, ongoing discussion regarding recent developments involving refuse and recycling services will likely necessitate a rate increase for trash service in mid-FY23 or beginning FY24.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recaSm0PXLgOmefo6","recILQjG3bunQR0s8","recx3J6Gl3qlC5bMI","recGGzf4fV3y01tu7","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_013","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec0itHTJoPGZBJxc","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Are rates for emergency medical services (EMSA) set to increase in FY23 for Tulsa residents? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No.**  According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \"There are currently no changes to the rate for emergency medical services in FY23\". Households within Tulsa's city limits are currently billed $5.45 per month for EMSA, unless a household chooses to opt out and pay for EMS services out of pocket if and when necessary. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recoJSpwBlG6Tx4G3","recP4EVMzwQakaDpC"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_014","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec03IVjFP0NWWPXc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa's FY23 budget reinvest the share of sales tax dedicated to the \"Improve Our Tulsa II\" program? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \n> This budget includes** $36.9 million in sales tax funded projects from the 2022 Improve Our Tulsa II program.** This program includes funding for critical projects for Police, Fire, Parks, Citywide Public Facilities, Economic Development Infrastructure, Transit rolling stock and Capital Equipment. Priorities in this year’s budget, include $3.9 million for apparatus replacement for the Fire Department, $4.0 million to fully fund the construction of a new parking garage for the Veterans Hospital to be constructed in downtown Tulsa and $14.3 million for Capital Equipment.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recs2KbDOv7pV75Sy"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_015","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec0GqNINkoAkY2UJ","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much is the City of Tulsa directly investing in utility system infrastructure for FY23?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 Capital Budget \n> ...provides $49.8 million for water treatment plant work, supply system repairs, water line replacement and relocation projects. Additionally, $33.4 million will be used for sewer treatment plants, pipe replacement and other system work. Storm water will receive $5.4 million for storm water pipe extensions, drainage improvements associated with roadway projects, small critical drainage projects and detention pond rehabilitation.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recQ4YQuzC7U20psh","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv","recXIehUTkifUvxMa","recC80WE0BC0GjA20","recWdnRM6FA93ACEx"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_016","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec1SOEcxrDe0o6nQ","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How is the City of Tulsa using realized and anticipated tax revenue from the \"Vision Tulsa\" economic development capital program? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \n> The City has now received over five years of collections from the sales tax approved by voters in April 2016 for the Vision Tulsa economic development capital program which is set at 0.805% for the next three years. Implementation of the project scheduling and financing plan continues. All of the planned revenue bond sales have been completed totaling $346.6 million to provide advance funding for 26 projects. The $510 million program will last 15 years. Directly funded projects total $65.3 million in the proposed budget for nine projects, with the largest allocation going toward debt service.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recqHZ3UmD7SG9v5v","rec2bz2lvTwnSaZRh"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_017","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13-14, Paragraph 5, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec1Fd4NXUebLuw7B","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Where is the City of Tulsa prioritizing cash investment for capital improvement projects over the next five years? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City's Capital Plan \n> ...Focuses on projects that should be considered for funding in the next five years, totaling **$553.6 million**. Close to two thirds (2/3) of the projects are renewal of existing infrastructure with the balance supporting growth. **The plan is dedicated to utility system projects** over the next five years as other recently approved capital programs have funded the majority of the City’s other capital needs.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","rec6lAkGREv8TvMN4","recI2ycsxZZO6fcFB","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_018","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 14, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec1KHjVeNQjYpJwh","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much debt does the City of Tulsa plan to incur in FY23 in the form of general obligation bonds, and for what purpose? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \n> During the upcoming fiscal year, the City anticipates undertaking an issuance of** $117.4 millio**n in general obligation bonds**. **All funds will go toward** street project**s authorized in the 2014 Improve Our Tulsa program and 2020 Improve Our Tulsa II program. Some** $14.8 million in bonds and loans will finance sanitary sewer and storm water project**s that include concrete pipe replacement, interceptor rehabilitation, sewer line rehabilitation and a storm water outfall line from Hager Creek to the Arkansas River. Funds will be appropriated by budget amendment upon completion of each bond sale. Taken together, these** **bond sales will add **$132.1 million **in additional funds to the capital budget, bringing the amended total to** $253.5 millio**n.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recG1IUnFd4nJ1taA","rec6lAkGREv8TvMN4"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_019","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 14, Paragraph 3, 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec2i1S5O7ZsQv1sc","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is the City of Tulsa doing to expand access to municipal court services? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["courts"],"Answer":"The City's budget for FY23 \"funds an additional prosecutor to facilitate the implementation of a night court in the municipal court system.\" City Council Chairperson, Lori Decter Wright, said in her budget address that night court will \"increase accessibility to citizens who are unable to appear before our courts during their regular working hours\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reckivnhvEWyCJLZu","rec5zuQYV86Tl6otE"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_020","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 15, Paragraph 6_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec2k9rNXRjPpvFhd","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa's FY23 budget address mental health services? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"In preparing this budget, City Council prioritized expanding the Community Response Team (CRT). This budget increases CRT's mobile mental health crisis response funding by $250,000 to further \"assist people suffering a mental health emergency and reduce reliance on other emergency services\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recYkpPYV94SIDMhN","recZQMiK01PQGJWUu","rec797k3CYC8F5O3f"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_021","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 15, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec3jrs83FZbjnCoO","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa's FY23 budget further progress on the Kirkpatrick Heights-Greenwood Master Plan? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"This budget funds $2 million toward implementation of the plan, \"which will create a vision and framework for redevelopment of 56 acres of publicly-owned property\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUfSeD3Kz5KHqfr","recF9VXTa1EcM719b","recYIMb0VrUFDleyD","rect27FgMNC6spxhc"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_022","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 15, Paragraph 7_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec3r2UFtQejntCwc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa's FY23 budget contribute to memorializing the victims of the 1921 race massacre? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, \n> This budget includes $1 million to continue the search for the graves of victims of the massacre, including funds for additional excavation and DNA analysis following recommendations from technical experts.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recWZneru5S6jTv3b","recfmDr9RyWV0rCGV","recybi21BpWHEijDu"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_023","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 15, Paragraph 7_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec4QlKD4fgrQOe3V","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What are the major areas of compliance that Tulsa city officials must adhere to when crafting the annual budget?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"City of Tulsa Financial policies address the following.\n\n- **Strategic planning**\n- **Operating budget**\n- **Risk management**\n- **Procurement and purchasing**\n- **Revenues**\n- **Capital budget and improvements**\n- **Long term borrowing**\n- **Investments and deposits**\n- **Reserves**\n- **Accounting**\n- **Trusts and authorities**\n- **Pension funds. **\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recYi0YH7AoRWSYI0","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec6MHeMdPDX7tVH2","recYp97CvgQUkDeRu"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_024","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16-19, Paragraph 1-5, 1-3, 1-4, 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec4qCBhfn0ynbEHN","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What are the policies governing how Tulsa city officials must approach strategic planning? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's budget policy, \n> 1.) All planning activities, strategies and studies should be comprehensive and integrated on a City-wide basis and 2.) Plans, strategies and studies shall encompass multi-year time frames and be updated annually.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recMu7qTaz3N2KCso"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_025","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recv1DWIEkBxAILJu","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does state law impact the City of Tulsa's budget-making process?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Oklahoma Municipal Budget Act is the primary state statute which lays the ground rules for municipal budget-making. In Tulsa, it's the responsibility of the Mayor (through the Department of Finance) to ensure compliance with relevant state law and the timely preparation of the City of Tulsa's annual budget.  \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUQrAdICNL7AVV3","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recXVgF1cWfOtbdGR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_026","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recxn1NjDkOGBVTXq","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"After the fiscal year closes, how can the public find out if The City of Tulsa ends up spending more or less than the amount that's budgeted at the beginning of the fiscal year?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The city maintains a budgetary control system to help it adhere to the budget. The public can find out how closely the City adhered to its annual budget by reviewing [Annual Comprehensive Financial Reports](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/government/departments/finance/financial-reports/annual-comprehensive-financial-reports/), which compare actual revenues and expenditures to budgeted amounts. Completed ACF reports are due no later than 6 months after the end of the fiscal year. The annual budget also shows projected versus actual revenues and expenditures for at least the most recent fiscal year. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUQrAdICNL7AVV3","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recXVgF1cWfOtbdGR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_027","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recyQafES0fUJlDlb","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How far in advance does the City of Tulsa try to estimate future revenue and expenses? And how do officials use that information?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Each year, and as part of the budget-making process, the City updates revenue and expenditure projections **for the next five years**. Projections include estimated operating costs of future capital improvements that are included in the capital budget. The City projects its equipment replacement and maintenance needs for the next several years and will update this projection each year in order to develop a maintenance and replacement schedule. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUQrAdICNL7AVV3","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recXVgF1cWfOtbdGR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_028","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recyFZh17SRJ4rnDQ","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What happens if the City of Tulsa has surplus funds left over at the end of the fiscal year? Can officials \"roll\" those funds over into their calculations for the upcoming fiscal year?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"State law and municipal policy aim to prevent a significant budget surplus or deficit by mandating that municipal officials adopt a _balanced_ annual budget. According to City of Tulsa budget policy, \n> It shall be the goal of the City that current operating revenues will be sufficient to support current operating expenses and** in no case shall more than five percent (5%) of the operating budget be supported using prior year's fund balances.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUQrAdICNL7AVV3","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recXVgF1cWfOtbdGR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_029","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recyJ2swApIggK3PI","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How often do officials review pricing for utility services provided by the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Per City policy, officials examine adjustments to Water, Sewer, Storm water and Solid Waste Disposal service rates and fees on an **annual basis** as an integral part of the City's budgetary process. Per budget policy, \"the City establishes all user charges and fees at a level related to the cost of providing the services\" .\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUQrAdICNL7AVV3","recTfZllChvyNKn9v","rec5KZdLje0u9mbEn","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_030","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 -Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reczcp0crORqDPwre","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What are Tulsa's policies regarding how city officials manage financial risk?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Municipal budget policy states the following:\n- \"The City will operate a risk management program to provide for protection against loss and a reduction in exposure to liability. Such program shall include an employee safety training program to minimize financial losses to the City\".\n- \"The City will establish a self-insurance program to provide for protection against major losses and will purchase excess coverage insurance to cover catastrophic losses where appropriate\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recNDEQTaKSNXVxn6","recryw6YTFtLo3PVp","recbzwYw7Dr0NSR8c","reckoTqYqO2SupOMG"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_031","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recz6XkUb8gogien4","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What are the policies governing procurement and purchasing for the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Municipal budget policy requires the City of Tulsa to operate a consolidated Purchasing and Procurement System, which \"...shall encourage full and open competition\" on all purchases and sales of surplus property via competitive bidding whenever possible.\"\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recYiiP3RcVALFX2h","reciK8ERaBnuCNfZM","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recJa5EWQoYMHDXk1"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_032","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reczaQvorqbSMKQAv","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What kind of municipal revenue qualifies as \"enterprise funds\" in Tulsa's annual budget?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Enterprise funds include the operating and capital funds of various city services (such as utilities) where the public is charged a fee based on usage. The city's general fund receives revenue from enterprise funds annually via a payment-in-lieu-of-taxes scheme. Other enterprise funds include emergency medical services, solid waste collection, and the sale of leases on city-owned property.  Enterprise funds contribute to the City's goal of maintaining \"a diversified and stable revenue system to shelter it from short-run fluctuations in any one revenue source,\" as outlined in municipal budget policy. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recumoqhRUNLtRKmo","recLdxp1w3fl7G4W9","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_033","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16-17, Paragraph 5, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recAf9HR6BLt3xDIz","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage receivable debt owed by outside parties?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to municipal budget policy regarding revenue management, \"The City of Tulsa will neither begin business activity nor continue to engage in business activity with an entity that owes the City funds from a delinquent debt\". The City, at its discretion, may choose to extend credit for certain obligations. However, \"if payment is not timely, the City reserves the right to refuse future credit as well as take necessary legal action to obtain payment of the debt and collection costs.\" \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recvHAmUPPPfP2P2V","recgTWazARLYOpVkS","recDbaiqqDl6xBtS6"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_034","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 16-18, Paragraph 5, 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recAsakq50VvmgCA0","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa fund its capital improvement projects?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to municipal budget policy, \"The City shall maintain a balanced mix of financing for funding capital projects, including **pay-as-you-go, grants and debt, without excessive reliance on any one source**. No capital project which does not comply with the provisions of and is not contained in the currently approved Capital Improvements Program shall be funded.\" \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recI2ycsxZZO6fcFB","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recTGx0H50NHZXRje"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_035","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recBLQvnyOqgSY4fL","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What criteria do Tulsa city officials use to evaluate potential new capital improvement projects? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to municipal budget policy, capital projects are scheduled based on the following criteria.\n\n- \"The project has been certified by the Planning Commission as being in accordance with City plans\n- The project will alleviate a service deficiency or replace a deteriorated and/or non-functioning facility\n- Federal or state law requires it to be done\n- Federal or state matching funds are available for the project\n- A Federal or state agency will construct the facility at no cost to the City\n- The project will encourage economic development\n- The project is needed to solve an emergency situation\n- The project will improve the quality of life in the City's neighborhoods\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recI2ycsxZZO6fcFB","reca5Zgna7r4QI3JP"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_036","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recBUMYkSorrc7Nfq","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Do Tulsa residents have a say in what capital improvement projects get approved? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** Public hearings are held before deciding what projects to include in any multi-year capital program, which requires approval by the City Council in the form of an adopted ordinance as part of the annual budget process. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recsDSESmuePsplUQ","recI2ycsxZZO6fcFB","reca5Zgna7r4QI3JP","recaahrH7a6kRGqnX"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_037","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recBHw8e8qRuBjt99","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Under what circumstances is it acceptable for the City of Tulsa to incur debt by issuing bonds? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, \n> \"General Obligation and Revenue** **Bonds shall only be issued for capital improvements and maintenance, or expenditures related thereto. Revenue bonds shall be used to finance capital improvements wherever possible. No operating expenses shall be funded using any form of long term financing\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recQ7YxWailsV4J0j","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recTGx0H50NHZXRje"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_038","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recCgyiBBIRn9yElm","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What's the maximum amount of debt that the City of Tulsa can carry at any given time?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Municipal policy prohibits total debt from exceeding the following.\n\n> \"...such levels as to cause the City's credit rating to be impaired, and in all cases the City shall take such actions and adopt such policies and procedures as necessary to maintain a rating equal to at least AA for general obligation debt.\"\nAdditionally, \n> \"In no event shall the net general obligation debt exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the net assessed market valuation of the taxable property of the City of Tulsa as established by the County Assessor\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recQ7YxWailsV4J0j","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recTGx0H50NHZXRje"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_039","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recC9ACxGlJV48u8t","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What's the maximum timeframe over which the City of Tulsa can finance projects using debt?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, \n> \"projects financed through the issuance of debt shall not be financed for a period that exceeds the expected useful life of the project and in no event shall the term of any debt exceed twenty-five (25) years\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recQ7YxWailsV4J0j","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recTGx0H50NHZXRje"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_040","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 17, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recCHPmcHNW9AdVbc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How must Tulsa city officials structure the sale of municipal bonds? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, \n\n> \"bond sales shall be structured to achieve level debt service payments to the extent possible, taking into consideration the costs of such financing. Either variable or fixed rate financing may be used, subject to applicable laws, depending on the cost benefit to the City of each option. Competitive sale shall be used for all general obligation debt issuance of the City of Tulsa. Negotiated or competitive sale may be used for revenue bonds.\"\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recQ7YxWailsV4J0j","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recTGx0H50NHZXRje"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_041","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 18, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recCIN2h6sbaoNhxa","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Who is responsible for managing the City of Tulsa's investment portfolio? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, \n> \"responsibility for the investment program of the City shall be vested with **the Director of Finance **who shall establish an investment program consistent with an adopted investment policy\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_042","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 18, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recD1fw4brTHlXZJz","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What criteria do City of Tulsa officials use to evaluate investment opportunities for public funds?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, \"it shall be the objective of the City of Tulsa to pool and invest public funds in accordance with current legislation and the Charter of the City of Tulsa. Criteria for investing shall adhere to the following order of priority: **(1) Safety, (2) Liquidity, (3) Yield**.\"\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_043","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 18, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recEhnWMgQ0uC3JzL","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage its cash flow? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa budget policy, this is conducted through a cash flow management system\n> \"...which includes the preparation of a cash flow analysis of all funds on a regular basis. Disbursement, collection, and deposit of all funds will be scheduled to ensure maximum investment return and cash availability subject to the City's investment policies. The cash flow management system shall ensure the City can offset significant downturns in revenues which could not have been reasonably foreseen and provide sufficient working capital and cash for daily financial needs\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","reccdgNZiuzQArflV"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_044","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 18, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recFZIMz4Wbs0mJga","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Does the City of Tulsa have safeguards to prevent and/or identify misappropriation of public funds? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes. **City of Tulsa policy mandates that all financial transactions \n> \"be audited annually by a recognized independent certified public accounting firm and such audit results shall include a management letter detailing areas where improvement is needed. A firm to perform such audit shall be chosen not more than once every five (5) years\".\nAdditionally,\n> \"the City shall prepare and issue an official Comprehensive Annual Financial Report no later than six (6) months following the fiscal year-end in accordance with Government Finance Officer's Association and Governmental Accounting Standards Board principles and standards. The City of Tulsa shall also must maintain an accounting control environment to help ensure proper authorization for financial transactions and proper procedures for safeguarding assets\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recuPnWiwcIIaduno","recUvr48FfuQXdJa3"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_045","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 18, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recFzDNEQcFyIQDVv","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What are the sources of revenue for the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa categorizes its revenue streams in three broad categories.\n- **Taxes**, which account for 54% of total municipal revenue.\n- **Enterprise funds** (the profit from goods and services sold by the City to the public for a fee), which account for 35% of total municipal revenue.\n- **\"Other\"** **revenues**, which account for 11% of total municipal revenue. \"Other\" revenues include proceeds from issuing licenses and permits, state/federal/county grants, \"general government\" revenue, fines and forfeitures, investment income, and \"miscellaneous\" revenue. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recs4ACxZb3cyhEps","rec1T067E2iYoXi7t","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recKE790vQbaHmbeM","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","recF1C0AXTd58Ca6d","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_046","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 1, Figure 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recFByptpi5sFwfNc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What gets taxed by the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa collects taxes in five major categories.\n- Sales taxes\n- Use taxes\n- Franchise taxes/Right of Way user fees\n- Hotel/Motel taxes\n- Ad Valorem Taxes. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recqHZ3UmD7SG9v5v","recEmq1qtcdXQWe3u","recObJx9f9qS9Npke","recBzl6uNMkwRCH5O","recwzQcFDQjFVInCO"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_047","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 5-6, Paragraph 2-5, 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recFK6JPCXWcwgFa5","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa tax private sales and what is the money used for? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa taxes sales at 3.65%. 2% goes into the General Fund to support city operations. 1.6% is split between the 2019 \"Improve our Tulsa\" program (.45%) and the \"Vision Tulsa\" (1.15%) funds. The remaining .05% is held in the city's Economic Stabilization Reserve. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recqHZ3UmD7SG9v5v"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_048","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 5, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recIQqW4x3mD93DbA","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is a \"Use Tax\" and how does the City of Tulsa use that money in its budget?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa applies a 3.65% tax to personal property which is purchased outside the State of Oklahoma and used within the city. 3.1% goes into the General Fund to support city operations. The remaining 0.55% is allocated to the 2016 \"Tulsa Economic Vision\" Fund. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recEmq1qtcdXQWe3u"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_049","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 5, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recKhEzYfGNFaBBf1","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Who pays franchise taxes/right of way user fees to the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa collects taxes and fees from utility service providers and telecommunications companies that build and maintain infrastructure on city-owned rights of way in order to deliver their service to residents and businesses. Revenue from this tax scheme is projected to be $30.4 million in FY23. Almost 50% of that revenue is paid, collectively, by Oklahoma Natural Gas and Public Service Company of Oklahoma.  \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recObJx9f9qS9Npke","recE95h3mqnQmyHTc"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_050","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 5, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recKUVVLNsIMxKdXh","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What's the tax rate on hotel and motel bookings in the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa taxes hotel and motel room bookings at **5%**. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recIMTVJuBGTTlkrk"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_051","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 6, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recK8E0Fc8WP0hqxk","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is an \"Ad Valorem\" tax and what does the City of Tulsa use that money for? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Ad Valorem is Latin for \"according to value.\" In practice, an ad valorem tax in the State of Oklahoma is a property tax. According to the State Constitution, Tulsa must receive sufficient ad valorem taxes each year to make scheduled payments on municipal debt and to cover the value of court judgements granted to plaintiffs who successfully sue the city. Ad valorem tax revenue is deposited into the city's \"sinking fund\" specifically for those purposes. The sinking fund in not treated as a part of Tulsa's operating budget. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recwzQcFDQjFVInCO","rec4YeQSwcGTc0Izx","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recryw6YTFtLo3PVp","recCRAEN2KiJtgHeW"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_052","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 6, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recKIRcYd5YAsUXdH","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much revenue does the City of Tulsa receive from state taxes on vehicle licenses, liquor, gasoline and tobacco? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"For FY23, the City of Tulsa projects receiving an **$8.1 million** share of state tax receipts. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recbJf8dAMpIEg3vL"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_053","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 6, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recL9BeTSdUyK13IF","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much funding does the City of Tulsa receive in the form of state and federal grants? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city revenue"],"Public":true,"Answer":"For FY23, the City of Tulsa projects receiving **$7.3 million** in grant funding from the state and federal governments. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recHVrvwsN9Bgch79","recpYxAcustPTx57u","recBxiII0dQVKFkrW"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_054","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 6, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recLq2IkHRBAxnKLr","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How do the Mayor of Tulsa and City Council describe their long-term goals for improving quality of life? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to FY23 budget documents, Tulsa city government's top three goals for the next several years are the following.\n- Increasing the number of uniformed police officers.\n- Building cash reserves.\n- Providing annually satisfactory performance increases for the city's workforce.\nAdditional goals include the following.\n- Combating homelessness.\n- Increasing transit access to jobs.\n- Improving neighborhood conditions.\n- Continuing to work on equity indicators.\n- Improving economic development and commercial revitalization.\n- Improving tourism and destination districts.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recMu7qTaz3N2KCso"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_055","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 2 - Executive Summary, Subsection 24, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recLu4wsISSej0cnh","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa's FY23 budget expand municipal court services?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"This budget adds a new \"configuration coordinator\" position (at a salary of $80,000) to the court's staff to manage the online databases used by court officials and the public. This budget also includes funding for \"mass communication software that utilizes text and email reminders about upcoming court dates and payments due.\" As part of the effort to start up a night court, the FY23 budget also funds hiring an additional public defender specifically to cover expanded hours. Prior to this budget, the municipal court received Coronavirus relief funding \n> \"...that will support outreach programs, facility improvements, Mental Health Initiatives and Organizational Development. CRF funding will also fund additional support personnel, including \"administrative support, court reporters, and Spanish greeters\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recQmeWJXdEaiIVRR","recUwVPxMmsJF1Ew2"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_056","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 3, Paragraph 4, 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recMlb9api3t7g0hK","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How many sworn police officers work for the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"As of beginning of FY23, Tulsa PD employed** 943** sworn police officers.\n- 743 police officers.\n- 82 sergeants.\n- 83 lieutenants.\n- 23 captains.\n- 9 majors.\n- 3 deputy chiefs. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recN7fXO7AgEJLka9","recVswcqhjkahPslp","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_057","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 10, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recNcWdzLNb95xpXQ","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Is the City of Tulsa hiring more police officers? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes. **Although the total number of sworn police officers did not change from FY22 to FY23, the Mayor of Tulsa and City Council consider police recruitment to be one of the city's highest priorities. In FY23, the police department has $4.5 million in funding to enroll and train 90 cadets at the police academy. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recN7fXO7AgEJLka9","recVswcqhjkahPslp","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT","recqYViQPyUI9t0SW"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_058","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 6, Paragraph 5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recPfdIeMn4aS6jmU","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does it take to run the Tulsa Police Department? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"For FY23, Tulsa PD has an **operating budget of $144.8 million**, and an additional $4.5 million budget for new and/or upgraded equipment and technology. The PD's total budget increased by $26.7 million (approx. 21.7%) from FY22 to 23. The largest share of police department funding, $118.3 million or 79.2%, comes from the City of Tulsa's general fund. The balance of funding comes from dedicated sales taxes and court fees. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recN7fXO7AgEJLka9","recVswcqhjkahPslp","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_059","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 7, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recPiUDXZgx741hfR","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Why did funding for the Tulsa Police Department increase by more than 20% in one year? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Some of the largest line item changes in the FY23 police operating budget include the following.\n- An additional $14.78 million for benefits and compensation.\n- $3.4 million to replace 80 marked police vehicles.\n- $3.4 million in overtime compensation.\n- A one-time appropriation of $1.2 million to replace tasers and associated equipment.\n- $1.2 million for internal equipment maintenance. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recN7fXO7AgEJLka9","recVswcqhjkahPslp","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_060","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 7-8, Paragraph 3, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recP6f8ViefZ8ZbTQ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Is the Tulsa Fire Department hiring members? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** The Tulsa Fire Department is enrolling 30 cadets in the training academy in FY23 at a cost of $1.28 million and plans to train an additional 30 in FY24. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recEH79RCbuqL9b2s","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_061","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 12, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recP61UvotZYLEdTI","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does it cost to run the Tulsa Fire Department? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Tulsa Fire Department operating budget for FY23 totals **$91.7** **million** dollars, with an additional $3.9 million dollars for upgrades to equipment and technology. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recEH79RCbuqL9b2s","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_062","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 12, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recPqpOe3yEMlRnab","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Why did funding for Tulsa Fire Department increase by $10 million in FY23 instead of remaining stable (as was initially planned)?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 Fire Department operating budget includes a $5.1 million increase in benefits and compensation in order to \"address recruitment and retention issues\". Additionally, from FY22 to FY23, the fire department's operating capital increased from $610,000 to $4.5 million. According to the Department highlights section of the FY23 municipal budget, \n> \"The Tulsa Fire Department was awarded a grant to reimburse the cost of sixty new firefighters for three years. As a result, Tulsa Fire Department will utilize those savings to fund operational support replacements and accelerate the replacement of needed fleet equipment in FY23 through FY25\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recEH79RCbuqL9b2s","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_063","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 11-12, Paragraph 4, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recPGSpD93NzAfMOI","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people does the Tulsa Fire Department employ?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The fire department's budget provides for a **743** person workforce. Of that, 725 staff are first responders or inspection/prevention professionals and 18 hold administrative/support roles. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recEH79RCbuqL9b2s","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_064","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 14, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recQZlGPXVfYJSb4y","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many parks are there in the City of Tulsa? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public assets"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa manages **135** parks covering roughly 6,553 acres. This includes the following.\n- Two nature centers.\n- Seven community centers (including WaterWorks Art Studio).\n- 57 miles of walking trails.\n- Two skate parks.\n- Three dog parks.\n- Five swimming pools. \nIn addition, there are 227 sports fields.\n- 132 diamond fields.\n- 95 rectangular fields.\n- 99 playgrounds.\n- 94 tennis courts.\n- 8 pickleball courts.\n- 29 basketball courts.\n- 36 half basketball courts.\n- 13 water playgrounds.\n- 18 splash pads.\n- 96 picnic shelters.\n- 4 golf courses.\n- 8 disc golf courses.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recj3NWnqBpmQn2Yx"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_065","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 21, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recQ5NxDypE15qvUN","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much money does Tulsa spend on parks and recreation? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The total parks and recreation budget for FY23 is **$18.7 million**. The budget includes $14 million in operation funds and $4.7 million for capital projects, equipment and upgrades. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recj3NWnqBpmQn2Yx"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_066","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 22, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recRJLx08YZQTGE2K","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed across Tulsa's parks and recreation facilities? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's parks and recreation facilities employ **175** people in total. 130 positions are full-time. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recj3NWnqBpmQn2Yx","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_067","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 24, Paragraph 1-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recT18BbTvdrkQe7g","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage its parks along the Arkansas River? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public assets"],"Public":true,"Answer":"River parks, including metro trails along the river and the Turkey Mountain Urban Wilderness area, are supported by shared investment between the City of Tulsa and Tulsa County. The $748,000 in resources allocated for River Parks are utilized for operational support to maintain the trails, Turkey Mountain Urban Wilderness, and rest room facilities along the trail system.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recj3NWnqBpmQn2Yx","recqvf34tgDHcMZrK","recsp7uZqHjxA2l3b"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_068","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 25-26, Paragraph 1-3, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recTyeq4hYDEEYyk2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Does the City of Tulsa outsource for management of any city-owned facilities? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public assets"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** The City has engaged in management agreements for the operations of City owned culture and recreation facilities. These facilities include the Tulsa Zoo, Mohawk Soccer Complex, Page and Mohawk golf courses, Performing Arts Center, and the Gilcrease Museum. The Parks and Recreation Department is responsible for the oversight for each of the management agreements. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recTs6J3JFZFlL2Xb","recf9MDE9d0hocJZD"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_069","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 29, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recUU3AZHM33FZ5tc","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What services are provided by the city's Working in Neighborhoods department?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"- Housing – to assist homeowners with emergency housing repairs and rehabilitation; prevent early institutionalization of the elderly; create incentives to develop affordable housing; and address substandard housing and revitalize housing through property maintenance and demolition. \n- Neighborhood Services – to increase opportunities for neighborhood reinvestment; serve as the contact between residents and the City to coordinate the delivery of public/private resources; and establish neighborhood associations and/or block groups to stabilize and improve neighborhood environments. \n- Neighborhood Investigations – to promote voluntary compliance and enforcement of City nuisance codes; provide a fair and unbiased enforcement program to correct nuisance violations and land use requirements. \n- Animal Welfare – operate the animal shelter and field services to provide a safe, healthy environment for companion animals; support and empower residents for successful pet ownership and educate about codes. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","reca7dWptHD12yNJx","recMTqjiET13Q8QWY","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","receanbM6igYUqV83","recs3820WK1JHT9tI"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_070","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 33, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec5af8c2Wj4lJqig","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much funding goes to support Tulsa's Working in Neightborhoods department?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The WIN department's total funding for FY23 is **$9.5 million**. The majority of funding comes from the City's general fund, while $1.3 million comes from intergovernmental Community Development Block Grants which mainly support housing initiatives. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","reca7dWptHD12yNJx","recMTqjiET13Q8QWY","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","receanbM6igYUqV83","recs3820WK1JHT9tI"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_071","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 34, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec5xBn66Tlp9QO7G","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is the City of Tulsa doing to improve quality of life at the neighborhood level? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through the Working in Neighborhoods department, Tulsa is allocating an additional **$200,000 to address nuisance abatement needs** for an FY23 total of $1.078 million. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","reca7dWptHD12yNJx","recMTqjiET13Q8QWY","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","receanbM6igYUqV83","recs3820WK1JHT9tI"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_072","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 33, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec5BGVZSb66F498y","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed by Tulsa's Working in Neighborhoods department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"As of beginning of FY23, the WIN department budget authorizes **83 positions**. Majority of positions are engaged in neighborhood investigations (30) and animal welfare (40). \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","reca7dWptHD12yNJx","recMTqjiET13Q8QWY","recD4xTSPIJ16uPjz","receanbM6igYUqV83","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_073","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 35, Paragraph 1-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec5DPPBTSeHQAdmx","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What agency in the City of Tulsa is responsible for approving development permits? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's **Development Services Department** is responsible for implementation of the City's development permitting process, including infrastructure and building plan review, and inspection services for all private development within the City of Tulsa.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recOO0Fn8e1VQ6zRQ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","rec1T067E2iYoXi7t","recTiRvU09wXMgM6J"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_074","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 36, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec6h0q8bhjVwxyIr","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What is the City of Tulsa doing to keep up with demand for building permit and licensing services? ","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending","service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 municipal budget includes** $88,000 in new funding **for the Department of Development Services **to hire two additional office assistants** to \"meet permit licenses and customer requests\". The City is also spending $334,000 to replace 11 SUV's used by inspection staff. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recOO0Fn8e1VQ6zRQ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","rec1T067E2iYoXi7t","recTiRvU09wXMgM6J"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_075","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 36, Paragraph 4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec77R1MCxJABvLcu","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many employees does the City of Tulsa have working to facilitate construction and development applications? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery","public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City's Development Services Department budgets for **72 staff**.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recOO0Fn8e1VQ6zRQ","recVypOtuYcUkJEnc","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","rec1T067E2iYoXi7t","recTiRvU09wXMgM6J"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_076","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 38, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec87hldcKTH6wYmQ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage its efforts to spur economic growth? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Public efforts to drive economic growth in Tulsa are primarily organized through the Tulsa Authority for Economic Opportunity (TAEO). According to the Authority, their mission is to \"create and manage public assets and resources to drive economic growth.\" \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recxAR0m4N9LBK6Ig","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","recsYLnM6D9nA05T7","recFGufMoITG3mFkw","rec0Hv8j1t0UEs5mi","recbqlsriU6IbD8JP"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_077","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 39, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec8oKLFePOBSB59t","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What services are provided by the Tulsa Authority for Economic Opportunity? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending","service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"TAEO services include the following.\n- Serving as the lead administrative entity for economic and community development services for the City of Tulsa.\n- Managing the City’s Tax Increment Finance (TIF) Districts.\n- Managing and supporting the City’s bond-financed economic development programs.\n- Executing land acquisition and disposition to leverage private development and redevelopment.\n- Leading asset optimization strategy related to major economic development assets; Managing Downtown Development and Redevelopment loan programs.\n- Managing the Affordable Housing Trust Fund and other housing development programs and incentives.\n- Managing outreach, education, and utilization monitoring for the City’s Small Business Enterprise program.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recxAR0m4N9LBK6Ig","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","recxSuwLECh4KWMK0","recsYLnM6D9nA05T7","recFGufMoITG3mFkw","rec0Hv8j1t0UEs5mi","recbqlsriU6IbD8JP"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_078","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 39, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec9Q88API3bDPi1Q","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What projects are in the pipeline for the City of Tulsa's Engineering Services Department? ","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending","service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Using $2.6 million in franchise fees collected by the City from the Public Service Company of Oklahoma, Tulsa's Engineering Services department is beginning the process to coordinate **burial of power lines located on public rights of way**. The department is also increasing staff in order to implement phase two of the City's **Stormwater Utility Enterprise Initiative**, in conjunction with the Streets and Stormwater department. Phase two involves scheduling and implementation of capital projects, using information from inspections conducted in phase one. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recG9ylp0H6MAQMf8","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","recXpWekkwgzWHRjd","rec6DzgUgFNoHl6AH","recjZ9tCiMS22I4GJ","recENjzNbe7BLE2Do","recXIehUTkifUvxMa","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_079","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 47, Paragraph 4-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recafrDEuMQWSfEaM","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"How many personnel are employed in Tulsa's Engineering Services Department?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Engineering Services Department employs **166** people. The department allocated $650,000 in FY23 to increase staff in preparation for several stormwater management projects. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recG9ylp0H6MAQMf8","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_080","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 47-48, 50 , Paragraph 5, 3, 1-4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recaYEVoejGZZJ9fm","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What City services are overseen by the Streets and Stormwater Department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Streets and Stormwater Department’s primary areas of responsibility include the following.\n- Street maintenance and rights-of-way inspections.\n- Traffic control.\n- Stormwater.\n- Land management.\n- Refuse and recycling service through the Tulsa Authority for the Recovery of Energy (TARE). \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recq4v6FtV3eR1DZe","recgN0fJS2rwWmNjM","recSlK0QKzpjweE7g","recseBfZYkw1A6Ldl","recchqDApy3QBKYYZ","recKnhYYUkb7Cz8mj"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_081","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 51, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recbkBTVrQKs8M9rR","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What is the City of Tulsa doing in FY23 to improve roadways? ","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Streets and Stormwater Department is receiving $1.9 million in the FY23 budget intended for the following.\n- Manage contracted services for utility pole removal\n- Traffic light conversion and expansion\n- Median maintenance and beautification. \nAdditionally, two inspectors have been funded to monitor streets and maintenance zones to aid the aforementioned efforts. Finally, two crew members are to be funded to remediate graffiti.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recq4v6FtV3eR1DZe","recSlK0QKzpjweE7g","reckHd94L8SRUXqLy"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_082","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 51, Paragraph 3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recbWFW4lpvdE1yx6","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does the City of Tulsa spend on maintaining its streets and stormwater infrastructure?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 operating budget for Tulsa's Streets and Stormwater Department totals **$81.4 million**. Funding for the department comes from a variety of sources, including transfers from: the City's general fund (21%), the Stormwater enterprise fund (29%), and the City's operating budget for sanitation services (38.9%).\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recq4v6FtV3eR1DZe","recjl1HzIv4cx3cKr","recXpWekkwgzWHRjd","recTSBaWiz8Jjukdr","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","recs5w170YqWhk0EG","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_083","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 52, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recc3K3qmNwCzvfRR","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed in Tulsa's Streets and Stormwater Department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 budget for the Streets and Stormwater Department authorizes **377** total positions. However, only 328 positions are considered full-time. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recq4v6FtV3eR1DZe","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_084","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 54, Paragraph 1-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recdzq4LREFunS7kV","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Where does the City of Tulsa's drinking water come from? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa’s drinking water comes from two sources: Lakes Spavinaw and Eucha on Spavinaw Creek and Lake Oologah on the Verdigris River. Lakes Spavinaw and Eucha are owned and operated by the City. Lake Oologah is operated by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. A third emergency source of water is available from Lake Hudson on Grand River. \n\nWater is treated at two treatment plants: Mohawk and A.B. Jewell.\nWater is provided to customers through a water distribution system. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recWTS365ZaJAii1V"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_085","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 55, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recdA3l0Oi3KZVT3s","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does the City of Tulsa spend to provide drinking water and treat wastewater? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 operating budget for Tulsa's Water and Sewer Department totals **$150.5** million, a 16.4% increase since FY22's budget. Officials attributed the budget increase to higher costs of chemicals and electric rates. Additionally, the Water and Sewer Department is budgeting $5.8 million for capital improvement projects in FY23. Operating revenue for the Sewer and Water Department mainly comes from service fees charged to users. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recWTS365ZaJAii1V","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_086","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 56, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"receQgb62kfWFwWhX","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed across Tulsa's Water and Sewer system? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's Water and Sewer Department budget authorizes **670 positions** in FY23. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recWTS365ZaJAii1V","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_087","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 59-60, Paragraph 1-5, 1-4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reces1VvdSwguyPok","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How far does Tulsa Transit service area reach? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa Transit provides public transportation serving residents in the City of Tulsa, Broken Arrow, Jenks, and Sand Springs. These services include fixed route bus service, ADA paratransit services for persons with disabilities, late evening service “Nightline\", and commuter bus service.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","reczzjXRKFQwHbmDu","recVcY0l0LzohS8bh","rec1ZoGmQ6gNQLiOP","rec4xZ8UeZVEnw4m6","recuHN8YzNu7H9T5b","rechuK1lfzzFzWSwU"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_088","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 61, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recgYNTUoE1hKUwxt","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does it cost to operate Tulsa's transit system? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa Transit's FY23 operating budget totals **$11.3 million**. The transit system's total budget also includes $1.2 million for capital projects. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recTIbOjRMIPffL0T","recD1AnBUORfwCKe9","recoDsrV2dKNJec5r","recrTEUGfP63fjd6V"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_089","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 62, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recgIGMPLppYbYBr8","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"How much funding goes to the office of Tulsa's Mayor? ","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["the mayor","city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 operating budget for the mayor's office totals **$1.5 million**, which represents a $104,000 increase from FY22. That increase was attributed to benefit and compensation adjustments. The Mayor's office FY23 budget also includes $1.6 million for capital spending, however the adopted FY23 budget didn't include a capital spending plan. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recm6eIXpywCU4s9O","recZ8wrSVc6ylH9Nv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_090","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 66, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rechbis79KYynrH2a","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work directly under the Mayor of Tulsa? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Besides the mayor, **14 people** are employed in their office. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recm6eIXpywCU4s9O","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_091","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 67, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rechbyjfajgjiGfHf","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is the role of the City Auditor of Tulsa?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Internal Auditor is responsible for keeping an independent watch over City operations and resources to ensure citizens’ resources are safeguarded and efficiently and effectively applied to the intended purposes. The mission of the City Auditor is to provide accountability of city government. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","recAYvgbBkz8u57cE"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_092","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 65, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recicLIvAoH2lvmUc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much funding goes to supporting the City Auditor's office? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 operating budget for the City Auditor totals **$1.4 million**. Funding increased by $171,000 since FY22, which included: $109,000 in salary adjustments, and $42,000 for technology. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","recAYvgbBkz8u57cE","recv9k4TDLtNQ4BHK"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_093","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 68, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reciMgq1aUybCf5RV","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in the Tulsa City Auditor's office?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Excluding the City Auditor themself, **11** people work in their office. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","recAYvgbBkz8u57cE","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_094","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 69, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reciNNzk3pAfnV2Ld","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Does Tulsa City Council approve a budget for itself? ","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** City Council's budget for FY23 totals $1.6 million. Council is funded entirely from the City's General Fund. Council's budget increased by $259,000 since FY22, with changes including: an additional $163,000 for compensation, $48,000 for a position that council deferred in FY22, and $15,000 to fund councilors' travel to conferences.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_095","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 70, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recinVYHseneJ0OgR","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed to support Tulsa City council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Excluding the 9 city councilors, Council's budget includes funding for **14 staff**. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recLaeh9i60oXfZoy","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_096","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 71, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reckQoxc8yyd94gTR","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa handle its legal affairs? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management","authorities, boards, & commissions"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City Attorney and the Legal department provide all the City’s municipal legal services. The department prepares and reviews ordinances, resolutions, executive orders, and contracts, and handles litigation, claims and controversies involving the City. Attorneys give advice and legal opinions to the City's elected officials, officers, employees, and to City boards, trusts, authorities, and agencies.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUwVPxMmsJF1Ew2","recDbaiqqDl6xBtS6","rec7ES4m8MO22n4gf"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_097","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 72, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reckRxIZktwqkmYF8","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"How much does Tulsa spend on its legal department? ","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 budget for Tulsa's legal department totals **$4.8 million**. Funding increased by $693,000 since FY22, including an additional $347,000 for compensation, and $289,000 to fund two new attorneys and a paralegal. 99% of legal department funding comes from the City's General Fund. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUwVPxMmsJF1Ew2","recZ8wrSVc6ylH9Nv"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_098","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 73, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recl9SY4gEudUUUN3","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many attorneys does Tulsa employ in-house?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's Legal Department FY23 budget includes funding for **23** City Attorneys, as well as 12 administrative/support personnel. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recUwVPxMmsJF1Ew2","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_099","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 74, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reclKGMmQcw3nB68G","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage its workforce? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through the **Human Resources Department**. Major responsibilities include the following.\n- Employment.\n- Compensation and Classification.\n- Occupational Health.\n- Workers’ Compensation.\n- Employee Development.\n- Insurance and Retirement Services. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reczzBRSwmcr3NBTl","recFXycyXWuWo47Ix","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_100","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 75, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recmIKJscZE6RGvN1","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does it cost to fund Tulsa's Human Resources department?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"FY23 funding for Tulsa's HR department totals **$30.3 million**, including funding for workers' compensation ($5.9 million) and employee benefits ($19.6 million), which are facilitated through the department. Excluding that funding leaves **$4.5 million for HR department operations**. HR department funding decreased by $1.8 million since FY22, reflecting a savings on insurance costs which was achieved through changing vendors. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reczzBRSwmcr3NBTl","recFXycyXWuWo47Ix","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_101","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 76, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recnD2wLwrPcQYgIV","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in Tulsa's Human Resources Department?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City's Human Resources Department FY23 budget authorizes **44** positions. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reczzBRSwmcr3NBTl","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_102","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 78, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recoRyH2BryE7rqWn","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What services does the City of Tulsa receive through its membership in the Indian Nations Council of Governments?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["INCOG","service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through the City Government's voluntary participation in INCOG, Tulsa receives assistance with the following.\n- City planning.\n- Transportation planning and programs.\n- Environmental and energy planning.\n- Community and economic development.\n- Aging services.\n- Public safety. \n\nINCOG also acts as a liaison between its member governments and superior (state and federal) governments, advocating for and monitoring legislation that impacts the Tulsa metro area. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec8vQgngrzM9iZpr","recXLUh3o33ckGqzF","recoJacT6bxOqTcxz","recFNDPHdW1uN7aK3","recfP45qdDq2WHR4k","recs3820WK1JHT9tI"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_103","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 81, Paragraph 1-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recoXr2lbsDXGHK1t","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much funding does The City of Tulsa contribute to the Indian Nations Council of Governments? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending","INCOG"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's FY23 contribution to INCOG is budgeted at **$3.3 million**.\n> ...resources allocated to INCOG will support services provided to the City of Tulsa for the following: land development reviews for TMAPC in accordance with the comprehensive plan; identifying and securing Federal and State transportation resources; identifying and securing Federal funding for economic development; and for the Destination District and Vibrant Neighborhoods programs.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec8vQgngrzM9iZpr","recXLUh3o33ckGqzF","recoJacT6bxOqTcxz","recfP45qdDq2WHR4k","recs3820WK1JHT9tI","rec3ifMUgWnqCRHMT","rechTLqF7JgRmiqKw"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_104","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 81-82, Paragraph 6, 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reco1m0uDfemvy5Kv","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"What are the main functions of Tulsa's Finance Department? ","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery","budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, Finance Department operations are carried out by eight divisions.\n- Administration.\n- Budget and planning.\n- Treasury.\n- Purchasing.\n- Accounting.\n- Utility services.\n- City Clerk.\n- Office of Performance, Strategy and Innovation.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reccdgNZiuzQArflV","recUvr48FfuQXdJa3","recNbV0kB3L2VPCAA","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec5hduOrQRpCn7TS"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_105","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 83, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reco8BFEctRkrbT2N","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What services does Tulsa's Finance Department provide to officials and the public? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa's FY23 budget presentation, services include the following.\n- Accounting for all revenues, expenditures, assets and liabilities.\n- Preparing the annual budgets and the capital plan.\n- Processing purchase requests.\n- Striving for the highest-possible return on the city's investment portfolio.\n- Paying all the city's bills.\n- Developing and implementing financial policies.\n- Administrating the City's debt programs.\n- Maintaining the billing system for utilities.\n- Analyzing financial data to inform officials' decision making. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reccdgNZiuzQArflV","recUvr48FfuQXdJa3","recNbV0kB3L2VPCAA","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec5hduOrQRpCn7TS"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_106","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 83, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recooO1gi4GCnD60Z","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in Tulsa's municipal Finance Department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's FY23 budget authorizes **161** full time positions.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","reccdgNZiuzQArflV","recUvr48FfuQXdJa3","recNbV0kB3L2VPCAA","recnRqKoBfg0sodUS","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec5hduOrQRpCn7TS"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_107","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 86, Paragraph 1-8_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recpfwOGnJ3QhDgKq","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does the City of Tulsa spend on its Information Technology Department?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's FY23 budget includes **$29.9 million** for the IT Department. Their net budget increased by $3.1 million from FY22. Major changes in the IT department's FY23 budget includes the following.\n- $1.1 million in salary increases.\n- $287,000 to hire three new positions.\n- $907,000 for the City's network security system.\n- $4.5 million to update or replace equipment. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rechspLKvrZieUeO6","recwqmsmyG37gRPXo"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_108","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 89-90, Paragraph 1-3, 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recpClPM617b5Xj98","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in Tulsa's IT Department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's FY23 budget, authorizes **122** IT positions, all of which are full-time.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT","rechspLKvrZieUeO6"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_109","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 91, Paragraph 1-4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recqfUGyxI75mZltx","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who can I call with questions or complaints regarding the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["report or request"],"Public":true,"Answer":"You can send all of your questions about the City of Tulsa to the Tulsa Policy Institute. Alternatively, Tulsa's 311 Customer Care call center bills itself as \"the central point of contact for the City of Tulsa\". Available through call, text, and online chat, the service features English and Spanish-speaking live operators who screen and try to resolve calls, or forward them to the proper city department. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recGkXnNzl0pw1ued"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_110","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 92, Paragraph 1-4_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recqT1gebcvfB0nU4","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does Tulsa spend to operate its information call center? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"In FY23, Tulsa is budgeting **$4 million** dollars for its 311 Customer Care Center. The budget increased by 61% since FY22. The department is budgeting $663,000 to hire and train an additional 13 employees, including 10 operators, to deal with increased call volume. Officials also hope to address retention with $375,000 toward compensation adjustments. And the City is spending $120,000 on translation services. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recGkXnNzl0pw1ued"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_111","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 93, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recq4Srjy5d4khhU3","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in Tulsa's information call center?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's 311 Customer Care Center FY23 budget authorizes **57** full-time positions. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recGkXnNzl0pw1ued","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_112","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 94_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recquggI48QHnc6oJ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How does the City of Tulsa manage its media and public relations efforts?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's **Communications Department** has the job of shaping how information about the city gets distributed to the public. That includes the traditional role of gathering information to provide to the press, interdepartmental communications, as well as social media/online content, and graphic design.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recSbuqxDsTNwX9nh","recqfb8JxzG6zMJoP","rec1kIEwUix0a4vuI"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_113","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 95, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recrepRcq85BCtYfr","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does Tulsa spend on its Communications Department? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Communication Department totals **$824,000**, a 26% increase from FY22. Budget documents attribute the increase to the need for increased messaging regarding COVID-19. The department is hiring a new graphics specialist at a $56,000 salary in order to meet that need. Existing salaries were also adjusted upward by $101,000 to address employee retention. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recSbuqxDsTNwX9nh"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_114","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 96, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recrLuxMWWVZleACV","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work in Tulsa's Communications Department? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Communications Department authorizes **9** full-time positions. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recSbuqxDsTNwX9nh","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_115","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 97, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recs3CiyjdTjhvcrG","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What department oversee parking enforcement in Tulsa? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Parking enforcement on streets and in public parking garages around Tulsa is overseen by the city's **Asset Management Department**. The same department is also responsible for repairing and installing parking meters, managing the city's fleet of vehicles, managing real estate holdings, and providing security for those properties. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec5EtmXDFLl7QB0k","recnOWL9qFDNEHXtK","rec7DEXH50BvqGg1U"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_116","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 98, Paragraph 1-2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recs4eqMmxCdtotTc","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much does Tulsa spend on managing its assets and enforcing parking?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The FY23 budget for Tulsa's Asset Management Department totals **$42 million**, a 25% increase over FY22's budget. A third of that increase is attributable purely to higher gas prices. The City is also spending $2.6 million on improvements to One Technology Center,  and $1.4 million to improve Air Force Plant 3. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec5EtmXDFLl7QB0k","recnOWL9qFDNEHXtK","rec7DEXH50BvqGg1U"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_117","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 99-100, Paragraph 1-3, 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recsyWdj9465DDtbs","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people work on parking enforcement and facility management for the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's Asset Management Department employs **132** people as of FY23. That includes 30 building operations staff, 17 security staff, 67 equipment management staff, and 17 administration staff. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","rec5EtmXDFLl7QB0k","recnOWL9qFDNEHXtK","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_118","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 101, Paragraph 1-3_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rectPnVpaxWPqeYnU","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"What is the City of Tulsa's credit rating? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["debt & credit"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to the FY23 budget, general obligation bonds issued by Tulsa are rated in the top-tier of creditworthiness by national credit rating agencies. Standard and Poor's rates Tulsa's creditworthiness at AA, their third-highest ranking (only three American companies hold the highest rating). Moody's rates Tulsa at Aa1, their second-highest rating. Higher credit ratings imply less risk, meaning Tulsa is more likely to get favorable repayment terms when it needs to issue debt. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","rec1u8SbNYk22AtgS","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl","recgTWazARLYOpVkS"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_119","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 103, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rectTLEgLXnQVwg2v","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How does Tulsa repay its debt? ","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["debt & credit"],"Public":true,"Answer":"There are two major forms of debt available to Tulsa: general obligation bonds and revenue bonds. \n\n**General obligation bonds** can be used to finance a wide variety of projects and can be repaid using almost any form of revenue, although some states restrict how municipalities can service general obligation debt.\nIn Tulsa, general obligation debt is paid off exclusively using a dedicated portion of property taxes.\n\n**Revenue bonds** are largely used to finance projects (such as toll roads) that will generate revenue upon completion. Revenue bonds are guaranteed with anticipated future revenue from the project being financed. Technically, the City of Tulsa has never issued a revenue bond. However, authorities (such as the utilities authority) associated with Tulsa have issued revenue bonds that benefit the City as well. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","rec49m6RsxVRmpzkl"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_120","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 103, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rectxTvEW3HoFWMOX","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much debt does Tulsa have on its books?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["debt & credit"],"Public":true,"Answer":"As of June 30, 2022, the City of Tulsa's total debt liability is **$395.3 million** on general obligation bonds issued as early as 2013 and as recently as 2022. The cumulative debt originally incurred across all ten currently-active bonds equals **$549.4 million**. The average interest rate for those bonds is **2.75%**. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec1u8SbNYk22AtgS","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recswu6dyA1AGVmzf"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_121","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 105, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rectJkLdNy5PHcLiE","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How long will it take for Tulsa to pay down the debt it currently holds?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["debt & credit"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa is currently liable for ten general obligation bonds (totaling $395.3 million) with varying maturity dates. According to FY23 budget documents, the City plans to satisfy all of its current debt by **2038**. Over that time frame, the City anticipates paying $49.4 million in interest, for a cumulative total debt service of $444.8 million. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","rec1u8SbNYk22AtgS","recjHJF8xuHGjzKjw","recswu6dyA1AGVmzf"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_122","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 104, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recujHcCWMLrJ4Oyh","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many people are employed by the City of Tulsa across all its departments?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["public management"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa's FY23 budget authorizes **4,120** positions. The actual number of employees is subject to change. Almost 75% of positions are in public safety or transportation/public works. City-wide, 4,015 positions are considered full-time. Total staffing increased by 67 positions since FY22. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recoDDlneXkTqmNsT","rechspLKvrZieUeO6"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_123","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 108, Paragraph 1-5_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recuzNAXLpwGmnhle","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"Does the City of Tulsa have a detailed breakdown of the costs to run its programs?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Dan","Concepts":["city spending"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** For the first time, Tulsa included a \"Program-Based\" budget as an appendix to its standard annual budget for FY23. **[The PBB](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/media/19042/04-departments.pdf#page=112) provides approximate costs for virtually every program** and service funded by the City of Tulsa. The PBB is useful because, in many cases, a single program may rely on collaboration from multiple City departments, making it difficult to calculate total funding from various department budgets. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recFo91PsG77aj1jR"],"Author":"Dan","QA Code":"Dan_Budget_124","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 4 - Departments, Subsection 111-140_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec638d4hB1GBsyyw","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I dispose of large furniture or appliances in Tulsa? ","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa residents can call 918-596-9777 to arrange for pickup of their large, bulky waste, including furniture and appliances. The cost for pickup is $10 per eight cubic yards.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","reck1kwu0Ax8s2U3s","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Dan_Planning_01","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 10._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recJr9JJWxjSVkEIC","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How much will I pay for water utility service in Tulsa in 2023?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**$4.31 per 1,000 gallons** of water used.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recWdnRM6FA93ACEx","reccm8jum85mxl4b2","recXrn5bEAziLS5hi","recGGzf4fV3y01tu7","recQ4YQuzC7U20psh","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Budget_X001","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 12, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recrQofXv9pfxknWX","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance"],"Question":"How much do I pay for sewage treatment in Tulsa in 2023?","Tags":["public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**$10.02 per 1,000 gallons of water** used per single-family home for FY23. In FY22, the cost of sewage treatment for the same water was $9.36.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recC80WE0BC0GjA20","recGGzf4fV3y01tu7","recqjX1JeotlsirPA","recXrn5bEAziLS5hi","recQ4YQuzC7U20psh","rec8kOYbGZaSstxXv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Budget_X002","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 12, Paragraph 2_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recijrAotbr9UfEfV","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What is the cost for emergency medical services (EMSA) in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["utilities & user rates"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Households within Tulsa's city limits are currently billed **$5.45 per month** for EMSA. Alternatively, households may opt out and pay for EMS services out of pocket.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recNlU5Iz5iBopJ9m","recoJSpwBlG6Tx4G3","recP4EVMzwQakaDpC"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Budget_X003","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Annual Budget FY 2022-2023. Section 1 - Policies, Subsection 13, Paragraph 1_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recqD75EpYH8AkM1s","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa provide any service or facility?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["service delivery"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes,** as long as it is \"for the common benefit or in the furtherance of any function performed by the city\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recyUhPcjsDzsScmC"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_001","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection C_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"receA6nhnlsmXDye6","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How would an income tax be instituted in the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect income tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". Also, it is possible for the State of Oklahoma to preempt such laws.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recu7T4jWaUtbDQ2V","rec2bz2lvTwnSaZRh"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_002","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection D_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec4pX9kHFNmS1NpQ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa change the sales tax?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through an election question voted in by a majority of voters. As it stands, the City of Tulsa may collect sales tax provided that such tax has \"been approved by a majority of the qualified electors of the City of Tulsa voting on the question at an election for the purpose of approving or disapproving of a proposed tax\". \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recrcssg4rJQBVqHI","recqHZ3UmD7SG9v5v","rec2bz2lvTwnSaZRh"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_003","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection D_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recZpTy0JHwRodHRh","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of revenue collection?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recKE790vQbaHmbeM","rech2pNnuhsCaWBdI"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_004","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection E_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recpPPdEz7MZiVoOh","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa issue licensing fees for the purpose of regulation?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recKE790vQbaHmbeM","rech2pNnuhsCaWBdI","recEs1TA3rbioFjib"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_005","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection E_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recq5W9EHslVikUs4","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa place additional taxes on homeowners for the purposes of funding specific projects in the area?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes**. In legal terms, this is referred to as the City of Tulsa's ability to \"levy and collect special assessments for benefits conferred\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","reck7kIoxu2H5u0Iy"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_006","Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection F_\n"},{"id":"rec15pfJPynMl1X9W","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa incur debt?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this","debt & credit"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recqFxYA8XapFzThA","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_007","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection G_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["revenue & spending","city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recGdKM2iFzCiNkBa","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa enforce endorinances on property owned, leased, controlled, or supervised by the city that is outside of its corporate limits?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["rec4hf7kl2KbCAAhf","rec6jAl0sv1feJZPs"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_008","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","policies & regulations"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection I_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recTxTS6OeaARRqxU","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa exercise jurisdiction over property that is outside of its corporate limits?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Yes, \"as authorized by the laws of Oklahoma\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["rec4hf7kl2KbCAAhf","rec6jAl0sv1feJZPs"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_009","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection J_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recspldZP1nlzy52h","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with states other than Oklahoma?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recSGySDo7WKcIwRl","recr78qUqkhp5Zz4o"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_010","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection K_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recdtjtiCncpMuELo","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who can the City of Tulsa enter into agreements with?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \n> ...enter into agreements with the State of Oklahoma; with another state or municipality; with any subdivision or agency thereof; with the federal government or any agency thereof; with private corporations, partnerships or individuals, or any combination thereof; and to exercise jointly all powers, privileges, and authority conferred upon the City of Tulsa by this amended Charter or by the laws of Oklahoma.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recSGySDo7WKcIwRl","recSZeWALNfnW3T8v","recr78qUqkhp5Zz4o","rec6snZ9f5cDYrdgN","recPuaZORpG9qS9b4","recbjRBkOBDM1mYbH","recBEtjHtOWJydWze"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_011","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection K_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recJyjW3gvNTDzkyN","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to waterports?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \n> ...acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec6jAl0sv1feJZPs","recBYNVooM0ZJAzf7"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_012","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection L_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recnW9By7HRQdAN1n","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What powers does the City of Tulsa have with respect to airports and air navigation facilities?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \n> ...acquire, plan, establish, develop, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, manage, equip, operate, regulate, and protect waterports, airports, and air navigation facilities within or without the corporate limits.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recS9VqXREVYUBP7z","recTxgKBjwHwkDitY"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_013","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection L_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recd8ZE3SOb02ZwLh","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What can the City of Tulsa appropriate and expend money for?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"appropriate and expend money for any public purpose\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_014","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection M_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec3I363fvWW148T2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can the City of Tulsa restrict and regulate the use of land?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes,** the City of Tulsa may \"restrict and regulate the use and subdivision of land, to perform planning and zoning, and to establish by ordinance the procedures therefor\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recEs1TA3rbioFjib","rec6jAl0sv1feJZPs","recSJYjYkV67eZeIy"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_015","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","policies & regulations"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection N_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recIhxRTYHzhHOkCj","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What can the City of Tulsa do to address nuisances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa may \"abate nuisances of any kind\" as well as \"assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land upon which the nuisance is located\". As of 2018, it has been clarified that the City of Tulsa \"may summarily abate a nuisance re-occuring on the same property under the same ownership within twenty-four (24) months of a previous nuisance abatement on that property\" as well as assess the expense thereof as a special tax against the land. This resulted from a 2017 vote through which 8,291 Tulsans voted in favor of this amendment against 2,123 Tulsans voting against.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["rec5zG09bsxqZaySm","rec6jAl0sv1feJZPs"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_016","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 1, Section 3 - General Grant of Power, Subsection O_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reccZDwuvvRKOWzLW","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is the composition of Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"City Council is \"composed of nine (9) Councilors elected by districts\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recRUsMirOWqHF097","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_017","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 1 - Creation and Function_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec99Jx7gE8SQRKU9","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is the salary of a City Councilor in Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"$24,000 annually\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recAi1b9s2ensb8nF"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_018","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 2 - Salaries_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec19A4qL1Ddrc7a6","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council vote to change its own salary?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No.** Prior to December 1st, 2014, this was not the case. Tulsa's City Council could change their salary by majority vote to go into effect after \n> ...the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recAi1b9s2ensb8nF"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_019","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 2 - Salaries_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec9TbZ4sOfNr41Gt","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Are Tulsa's City Councilors reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \"Councilors may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_020","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 2 - Salaries_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recBMe6cXMvNTvemj","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What are the minimum number of meetings that Tulsa's City Council must hold?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council must hold at least two (2) meetings every month and these meetings must be held at City Hall.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_021","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.1 - Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recV1NGVvYjXsiBKM","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who can call a special meeting for Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Finally, only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recZkq5S5jOSatcsk"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_022","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.1 - Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recf0ryGoDG3jEzsp","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How much notice must be given to each City Councilor prior to a special meeting?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_023","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.1 - Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recZ4n6AUIJ0Ko0pm","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What must be included in special meeting notices to City Councilors?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Written notice to City Councilors concerning special meetings must include the date, time, and place of the meeting. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. Only those subjects included in the written notice can be considered at special meetings. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call special meetings. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_024","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.1 - Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rectU1pwt8qsoVWOv","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can subject matters not included in written notice to Tulsa's City Council be considered in special meetings?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No,** only those subjects outlined in the written notice can be considered. Written notice must be delivered to each City Councilor at least 24 hours prior to such special meeting. Written notice must include the date, time, and place of the special meeting. This written notice can be served (a) electronically, (2) in-person, or (3) can be left at the usual place of residence of the City Councilor. The Mayor of Tulsa, the Chairman of the City Council, or one-third (1/3) of Tulsa's City Council may call such special meetings. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_025","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.1 - Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recPRhnZHJKzKejn1","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who can call a civil emergency in Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recuuCNjMbaMhXTVC","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec8VvbJAupXTEemd","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_026","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.2 - Civil Emergencies_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recZdIUA7H1Osj5N2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How do City Council meeting rules change during a civil emergency?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"During a Civil Emergency, City Council can meet for special meetings anywhere within the corporate limits of the City of Tulsa, without notice, and may consider \"matters as necessary for the preservation of the public health, safety, and welfare during the period of the emergency\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_027","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.2 - Civil Emergencies_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec2JgSrbjUMIUk5z","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is a civil emergency in Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Answer":"\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec8VvbJAupXTEemd","recdiRERCYuZGHSXd"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_028","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recNCBZjH7n7v19CU","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Are City Council meetings subject to open meeting laws?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recjQZSeuGijmUfoF"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_029","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 3.3 - Open Meetings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recVTBqVF05rHDqU4","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What are Oklahoma's open meeting laws?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Answer":"\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recex3pj2DIma2nV4","recjQZSeuGijmUfoF"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_030","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recN0icK4snpPTgPb","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council employ persons to assist the Council in the performance of its duties?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes,** Tulsa's City Council \"may employ such persons as are necessary to assist the Council in the performance of its duties\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recFXycyXWuWo47Ix"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_031","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec9qxJGbqTxskUt5","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who determines the rules and order of business of Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council \"shall determine and establish its own rules and order of business\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_032","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rechQA8rvXHXISFh2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recVig4UtVDrLlTTL"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_033","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec8dJ2DJyxY9UTGK","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine its own members for violation of Council rules?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_034","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"receT1bJaQ85jTJkX","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recVig4UtVDrLlTTL"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_035","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recT9LzcnQau9F8yn","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council fine persons for violation of council rules?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_036","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recgsD7FTLAPRdtda","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How much can Tulsa's City Council fine its members or other persons for a single offense?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**$100 dollars.** \n> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city. The vote of two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to impose a fine on a Councilor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","rec9rnEQuFVJq4IgH"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_037","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reccKNrXkFZuRcUOg","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How much of Tulsa's City Council does it take to impose a fine on a fellow City Councilor?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Two-thirds of the entire City Council. When each of the nine seats are filled, this means six Councilors must vote to impose such fine. \n> The Council may punish by fine its members or other persons for disorderly conduct at a Council meeting or for violation of Council rules. Any fine imposed by the Council for a single offense shall not exceed the sum of one hundred dollars ($100.00) and shall be collected in the same manner provided for the collection of other debts owed the city.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN","rec9rnEQuFVJq4IgH"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_038","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 4 - Rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recIFX9E7eyXzivSm","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who elects the Chairman and Vice Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman. Further, the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Duties can be assigned to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. The Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recb8y39G2n1fUMpf","recZtZB1zc9lOY8fl"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_039","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 5 - Chairman_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recbxyi0mWJZgy5ug","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who assigns duties to the Chairman of Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council assigns duties to the Chairman via charter amendment, ordinance, or rule of the Council. Further, Tulsa's City Council elects their own Chairman and Vice Chairman and the terms of such positions are determined by the Council. Finally, the Vice Chairman performs duties of the Chairman under conditions of the Chairman's absense.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recb8y39G2n1fUMpf"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_040","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 5 - Chairman_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec7hWblgWTNaz3fA","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Does Tulsa's City Council have the power to subpoena witnesses?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records\" for the purposes of judging the qualification of its members.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","receacjDdXCI7IGXt"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_041","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 6.1 - Judge of Qualifications_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recHBGL86X00WgBGI","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is the judge of the qualifications of Tulsa's City Councilors?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council is the judge of the qualifications of its members. In doing so, it has \"the power to subpoena witnesses and require the production of records. The decisions of the Council in such cases shall be subject to review by appropriate actions in courts of competent jurisdiction which shall be commenced within ten (10) days after a final decision by the Council\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recrCWf24cPQJ3bt8","recjzq9fpGN98fJ4l"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_042","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 6.1 - Judge of Qualifications_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recTW00UExSnnNQ0X","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many of Tulsa's City Councilors must be present to constitute a quorum for a meeting? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"A majority of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council must be present to constitute a quorum for City Council meetings. Further, \"less than a majority may continue a meeting to a specific date and time. The affirmative vote of a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall be necessary to adopt an ordinance or resolution\". Finally, actions of the Council are effective following an affirmative vote of a qurom.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_043","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 6.2 - Quorum and voting_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recqCXkT9BEA4Ujbc","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"When do ordinances go into effect?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Upon an affirmative vote of a majority of a qurom of Tulsa's City Council. Further, \"a majority of the entire membership of the Council shall constitute a quorom for a meeting of the Council\". However, as revealed in Section 9 of the City Charter, \"Ordinances adopting budgets, making appropriations, pertaining to local improvements and assessments, and any ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure shall take effect at the time stated therein. All other ordinances and resolutions shall take effect at the time stated therein, but not less than thirty (30) days from the date of first publication. Ordinances adopted by vote of the electors shall take effect at the time stated therein or, if no time be stated, thirty (30) days after the election. An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section. The vote of at least two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council shall be required to adopt any ordinance or resolution as an emergency measure\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_044","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 6.2 - Quorum and voting_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recI9hhWolXMWZInc","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How can Tulsans block a zoning change?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["zoning","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"By convincing the property owners impacted by the zoning change to file a protest against the zoning change, Tulsans can raise the bar for the number of votes required for the zoning ordinance to go into effect - instead requiring the City Council to have three-fourths (3/4) of the entire membership of the Council to enact the zoning change. Such protests must meet two requirements. First, protests must be filed at least three (3) days prior to the hearing of the zoning change by City Council. Second, protests must be supported by either (a) owners of at least 20% of the area of the lots included in the proposed change or (b) owners of at least 50% of the area of the lots within a 300 foot radius of the exterior boundary of the territory included in the proposed change.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recMGYhG1RlGmHr3b","recgdKPlaYC1v6B5Z","rec9HPiO516rCW9GX","reckXC0QQXYLxJRIn","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recov7WSAYmy4L4Qr"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_045","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 6.3 - Voting on zoning changes involving protests_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recJhuEB9AzgYUC2c","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of general funds?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recuuCNjMbaMhXTVC"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_046","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.1 - Budgets_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recEzaBNMAdt0bQ2c","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What must occur prior to Tulsa City Council's expenditure of funds from the sale or issuance of an obligation of the city, or from any other source?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Mayor shall submit to the Council a budget for the expenditure of such funds or amendments to previously adopted budgets. The Council shall adopt budgets or amendments and make appropriations by ordinance, provided, that no revenue derived from the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax, as set forth in detail in Title 43-I Tulsa Revised Ordinances, shall ever be budgeted, spent or used for any purpose other than public safety as described therein. \nThe special treatment of the 2017 Public Safety Sales Tax was the result of an amendment supported by 6,602 Tulsans. 3,640 Tulsans voted against the amendment.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recuuCNjMbaMhXTVC"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_047","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.1 - Budgets_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recEbVluDWBTk6MvJ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"What public hearings must City Council hold upon receipt of budgets from the Mayor?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"At least one public hearing, during which \n> ...any citizen of the city shall be given an opportunity to be heard on the budgets or any item or program recommended therein. After public hearing, the Council may adopt a budget or amendments. The Council may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recuuCNjMbaMhXTVC","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recov7WSAYmy4L4Qr"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_048","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.2 - Action on Budgets_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recsc2NopBFYEIkTO","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"How can Tulsa's City Council alter budgets submitted by the Mayor?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council \"may add, delete, increase, or decrease programs or amounts, except expenditures required by law\" with respect to the budgets recieved from the Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recuuCNjMbaMhXTVC"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_049","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.2 - Action on Budgets_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recrjcT3yucDREUEy","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council establish additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may establish by ordinance additional procedures for the preparation, adoption, and amendment of budgets, for the transfer of appropriations, and for supplemental and emergency appropriations which are not in conflict with the provisions of this amended Charter or with the laws of Oklahoma.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_050","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.3 - Additional procedures_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec3DfrbS7vyX9HcT","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"What is the purpose of Tulsa's Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Economic Stabilization Reserve assists to limit \"the amount of reduction required in the general fund budget during times of declining revenues\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_051","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.4 - Economic stabilization reserve created_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recfNzcg0IAtftZe9","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Where are revenues in excess of the projected General Fund to be allocated?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than four percent (4%), the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate the excess General Fund revenues as follows: \n> A. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n> B. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n> C. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n> The Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues. \n\n> The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve.\nThis must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B. However, for any of the aformentioned to go into effect, projected revenues must initially exceed $250,000, per section 7.10 of the City Charter.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","recpRzWgONB4fYLgm","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_052","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.5 - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recv6SfORNkvvGZFh","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"In what ways are the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council limited in adding money to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"While the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council may, at any point in time, authorize any available funds to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, the total in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed 30% of actual total General Fund revenues. When this 30% cap is met, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve. However, such capital, other one-time expenditures, and the operating reserve must not exceed 25% of the excess General Fund revenues. Finally, all of the aformentioned allocations are only required where projected revenues initially exceed $250,000, per Sectiomn 7.10 in the City Charter.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_053","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.5 - Allocations to the economic stabilization reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recKI2ljxk30sljQH","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"For what may the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council appropriate funds allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures for?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","recnMN6FZvUqfZPpr","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_054","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.6 - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recidhOdgYBwZGr4D","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Can capital funds be used to by the Mayor and Tulsa's City Council to purchase information systems?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** The Mayor and Tulsa's City Council \"may, at any time, appropriate monies from the capital and/or other one-time expenditures allocation for capital projects or for expenditures such as, but not limited to, acquisition of equipment or information systems\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","recnMN6FZvUqfZPpr","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_055","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.6 - Use of monies allocated to capital or other one-time expenditures_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recspUm1ijTd6LFwG","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"For what may the Mayor and City Council use funds allocated to general purpose?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, appropriate monies from the general purpose allocation for any lawful municipal purpose.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recALrXDVs83Qf9QT","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","rec5fkRItyK7VCWJO","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_056","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.7 - Use of monies allocated for general purposes_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recTjmf7h0JsMBHep","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Under what conditions may the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by Tulsa's City Council appropriate up to 50% of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve for any lawful municipal purpose?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> If the City Treasurer projects that total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will either (a) be less than the current budget year's total General Fund revenues, or (b) be less than the highest of any other previous year's total General Fund revenues, the budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the Council may appropriate up to fifty percent (50%) of the current balance in the Economic Stabilization Reserve, but no more than the shortfall in total General Fund revenues as determined above, to be used for any lawful municipal purpose in the upcoming budget year. For purposes of calculating any shortfall:\n> A. If the trigger for withdrawals from the reserve was not met in the current budget year, the City Treasurer shall calculate the shortfall for the upcoming budget year by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the total projected General Fund revenues for the current budget year.\n> B. If the trigger for withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve was met in the current budget year, the shortfall shall be calculated by subtracting the total projected General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year from the highest of any previous year's total General Fund revenues. \n\nAs outlined in Section 7.9 of the City Charter, the City may withdraw the percentage of negative growth in the Consumer Price Index if the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will be less than the index for the current budget year.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recpRzWgONB4fYLgm","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_057","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.8 - Withdrawals from the economic stabilization reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reclX64XyLqLyBccN","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Under what conditions is the City of Tulsa not required to allocate any anticipated excess revenues as outlined in the allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process","can they do this"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa is not required to allocate any anticiapted excess revenues for the upcoming budget year as outlined in the regulations concerning allocation to the Economic Stabilization Reserve if the City both (1) made appropriations from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the current budget year and in the immediately preceding budget year pursuent to regulations for withdrawls from the Economic Stabilization Reserve.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","reclEz2L2IRivna0C","recGP41AikxZaToKj"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_058","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.9 - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec2pPMYrzFv3tN4a","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Where adjustments to the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve are concerned, what product is the City Treasurer required to rely on when making projections for the Consumer Price Index?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The All Items Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI-U) - or its succesor as determined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, a bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","reclEz2L2IRivna0C","recGP41AikxZaToKj","recckkQsJ4fr64GLe","recpRzWgONB4fYLgm"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_059","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.9 - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reckg2u8lYxRiR9Id","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Under what conditions are allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve by the City of Tulsa triggered by a Consumer Price Index growth rate percentage (plus 2%) rather than the City Treasurer's projections that the total General Fund revenues for the upcoming budget year will exceed the total General Fund revenues for the current budget year by more than 4%?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"When the City Treasurer projects that the Consumer Price Index for the upcoming budget year will exceed the index for the current budget year by more than five percent (5%). When this happens, the following allocations are triggered: \nA. Fifty percent (50%) of the excess General Fund revenues to the Economic Stabilization Reserve;\n\nB. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated in whole or in part to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve; and,\n\nC. Twenty-five percent (25%) of the excess General Fund revenues may be allocated for general use consistent with lawful municipal purposes.\n\nThe Mayor and the City Council may, at any time, authorize any other available monies to be added to the Economic Stabilization Reserve; however, total monies in the Economic Stabilization Reserve shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of actual total General Fund revenues\". \"The budget submitted by the Mayor and approved by the City Council shall allocate excess revenues that would otherwise be allocated to the Economic Stabilization Reserve above the thirty percent (30%) cap instead to capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve\". \nThis must be conducted in accordance with the provisions of section B.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","reclEz2L2IRivna0C","recGP41AikxZaToKj","recckkQsJ4fr64GLe","recpRzWgONB4fYLgm"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_060","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.9 - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"rec6vh6TrFjUmFeM7","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Are revenue changes to the General Fund caused by actions made by Tulsa's City Council or voters counted as part of triggers for allocations to or withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve in the year in which the revenue change is made?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No**. If the City Council or the voters take any action that changes the amount of total General Fund revenues in any material manner, including but not limited to reducing a tax or imposing a new fee, the revenue changes caused by that action shall not be counted as part of the trigger for allocations to the Economic Stabilization Reserve during the year or years in which the action is first implemented.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","reclEz2L2IRivna0C","recGP41AikxZaToKj","recckkQsJ4fr64GLe"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_061","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.9 - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recdCamvwKlJcatpI","Tags_PreOctober":["public finance","governance process"],"Question":"Who is responsible for re-balancing the allocations to or withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve with actual revenue results (as stated in the City of Tulsa's independent annual audit) in conjunction with the annual year-end of close of the budget?","Tags":["public finance","governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City Treasurer.\n\nSpecifically, the City Treasurer is responsible for re-balancing the allocations to or withdrawals from the Economic Stabilization Reserve, Capital, Other One-Time Expenditures, or Operating Reserve with actual revenue results (as stated in the City of Tulsa's independent annual audit) in conjunction with the annual year-end of close of the budget,\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recdbpewxCXJ0tOiA","rec17CY4B97WAP1a8","reclEz2L2IRivna0C","recGP41AikxZaToKj","recckkQsJ4fr64GLe"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_062","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 7.9 - Adjustments to allocations to the economic stabilization reserve, capital, other one-time expenditures, or the operating reserve._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recuWHA3iHE79fvAO","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"In what form must ordinances and resolutions be introduced in Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"In written or printed form.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_063","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec6SBDNK5JI26Dln","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Which ordinances must be confined to one subject?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_064","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reckKii2LW5m97tDw","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Must ordinances be clearly expressed in the title of the ordinance?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> All ordinances or resolutions, except those adopting budgets, making appropriations, or adopting a code of ordinances, shall be confined to one subject, which shall be clearly expressed in the title.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_065","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recpHYt2lOwEEF0BV","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can ordinances that involve adopting budgets or making appropriations involve anything else?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No.** \n> Ordinances adopting budgets and making appropriations shall be confined to budgets and appropriations.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_066","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recLV3LnvqdegOJoy","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many meetings must an ordinance be on Tulsa's City Council agenda before it can be adopted?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Two.** However, Tulsa's City Council can waive this requirement with a vote of two thirds of the entire membership of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_067","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recOXIYuh7Rtab6da","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Must a copy of each proposed ordinance shall be furnished to each Councilor or left at the usual place of residence of each Councilor prior to final consideration?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_068","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec6va1lh2LBGFB49","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Must a vote of each Councilor shall be taken upon all matters before the Council and entered in the journal of the proceedings of the Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_069","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recpthUlJ6BuTMwer","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is the enacting clause for all of the City of Tulsa's ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"\"Be it Ordained by the City of Tulsa\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_070","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 8 - Procedures on ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recOwoV1vjiYKeivd","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Once the Mayor recieves ordinances voted in by the City of Tulsa, how long does the Mayor have to either approve or veto the ordinance?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**15 days.** \n> Within fifteen (15) working days following such delivery, the Mayor shall either approve or veto the ordinance or resolution. If vetoed, the ordinance or resolution shall be returned to the Council with a written statement of the objections of the Mayor. If neither approved nor vetoed by the Mayor in the time specified, the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. A veto by the Mayor shall suspend further action of the Council upon the ordinance or resolution for a period of seven (7) days, after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor. If the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec2sygWSOsXvZgta"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_071","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 9 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec4Edp6L9rClmdap","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to overturn a Mayor's veto of an ordinance?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of Tulsa's City Council are required to overturn a Mayor's veto. Once this vote takes place, the ordinance goes into effect as if supported by the Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec2sygWSOsXvZgta"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_072","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 9 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recfbiYlKz7UHnw1C","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How long does Tulsa's City Council have to wait after the Mayor vetos an ordinance before the Council can vote to overturn the veto?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Seven days, \n> ...after which the Council may override the veto by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership, and the ordinance or resolution shall take effect as though approved by the Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec2sygWSOsXvZgta"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_073","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 9 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recN1uqVTS4pZqnT7","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"If Tulsa's City Council fails to overturn the Mayor's veto on a given ordinance, how long must the Council wait before the ordinance can be reconsidered?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**90 days.** \n> If the veto of the Mayor is sustained, the subject of the ordinance or resolution, except ordinances adopting budgets or making appropriations, shall not be further considered by the Council for a period of ninety (90) days; provided, that the Council by a vote of two-thirds (⅔) of its entire membership may waive the ninety (90) day period.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec2sygWSOsXvZgta"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_074","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 9 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recJNNl1QCAtbnA5q","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What can Tulsa's Mayor veto?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor may veto or even reduce any item of ordinances that adopt budgets or make appropriations, unless otherwise provided in the City Charter.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec2sygWSOsXvZgta","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_075","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 9 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reczAl7vOqNBmJo0C","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How many votes are needed in Tulsa's City Council to adopt an ordinance as an emergency measure? ","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Two-thirds (⅔) of the entire membership of the Council are required. Further,  \n> An ordinance or resolution adopted as an emergency measure to provide for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, welfare, or safety shall describe the emergency in a separate section.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recArDxIzaR55Bg9n"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_076","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 10 - Approval or veto of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recTn3AyUsJ1ibicW","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who's responsibility is it to attest to and record ordinances and resolutions adopted by Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City Clerk.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recyFsZOyQSoHehhX"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_077","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 11 - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reckA9BJY7gm6wJSw","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How long does the City of Tulsa have after an ordinance is adopted to be published in a newspaper of general circulation?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**10 days.** \n> Ordinances and resolutions shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation within the city within ten (10) days after approval. Codifications of ordinances and codes of law adopted by reference need not be published in full unless otherwise provided by the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recyFsZOyQSoHehhX","rec1kIEwUix0a4vuI"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_078","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 11 - Recording and publication of ordinances and resolutions._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recAm60N924MH9Z5x","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is permitted to be omitted from the Code of Ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> Titles, enacting clauses, emergency sections, and temporary and special ordinances may be omitted from the code. Ordinances and parts of ordinances which are to be repealed by the adoption of a revised code may be omitted. A revised code may contain new matter.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recyFsZOyQSoHehhX","rec5ijDMdXSschS99","recArDxIzaR55Bg9n","recjo2zoepOIemiRP"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_079","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 12 - Codification of Ordinances_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recqnOIKAmNbYEoy2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is responsible for keeping copies of the Code of Ordinances to sell to the public?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City Clerk.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recyFsZOyQSoHehhX","rec5ijDMdXSschS99","recArDxIzaR55Bg9n","recjo2zoepOIemiRP"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_080","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 12 - Codification of Ordinances_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recSaLFbktsqMQLz7","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is responsible for revising and maintaining the Code of Ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's City Council\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec5ijDMdXSschS99","recArDxIzaR55Bg9n","recjo2zoepOIemiRP"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_081","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 12 - Codification of Ordinances_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec3Gdqrld0Bqkpe7","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe imprisonment as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec9rnEQuFVJq4IgH","recoCmCo16FXWqhx8"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_082","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 13 - Penalties for violation of ordinances._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec1KvYGWS0yxpQ7J","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe fines as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec9rnEQuFVJq4IgH","recxYIRPvYEut8lEN"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_083","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 13 - Penalties for violation of ordinances._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recQTitE6nlxInoQS","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council prescribe penalites as a punishment for the violation of ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of Oklahoma, prescribe penalties for the violation of ordinances, including fines and imprisonment.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","rec9rnEQuFVJq4IgH"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_084","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 13 - Penalties for violation of ordinances._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recx4gdgYZkazERi6","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How must Tulsa's City Council provide for review of the amended City Charter?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**By ordinance.** \n> The Council shall provide by ordinance for the periodic review of this amended Charter and shall submit to the qualified electors of the city amendments necessary to provide for representative, efficient, and economical administration of city government.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recd19wOCMV6gY71M"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_085","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 14 - Charter Review._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recOTqXp5EXhSgHUt","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Are the legislative powers of Tulsa's City Council subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> All legislative powers vested by this amended Charter in the Council are subordinate and subject to the rights of initiative and referendum reserved to the people by the Constitution of Oklahoma.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recex3pj2DIma2nV4","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec3gAkTXHxNLnke9"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_086","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 15 - Initiative and Referendum_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec6agCZvMp8gPJvx","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"By what means does Tulsa's City Council review administrative actions?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**By ordinance.** \n> The Council shall provide by ordinance for the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals by the divisions, departments, and agencies of the city. Except when otherwise provided by the laws of Oklahoma, the grant, issuance, modification, amendment, or revocation of orders, licenses, permits, certificates, and approvals shall be subject to review by the Council, upon petition by an aggrieved person, in accord with procedures which the Council shall establish by ordinance. The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recRACBybqeI1fCXf"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_087","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 16 - Review of Administrative Actions_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec8GbxgCBR62szM2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can Tulsa's City Council abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction with respect to administrative review?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No.** \n> The Council may not abrogate any right of review by a court of competent jurisdiction.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recRACBybqeI1fCXf"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_088","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 16 - Review of Administrative Actions_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recLHIqht7i85m0SZ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Concerning investigations and hearings, must City Council hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of city government?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council shall hear complaints made by citizens concerning the administration of the city government.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc","recaahrH7a6kRGqnX"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_089","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec7qQNL5eoBEBEQE","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council investigate the conduct of the city government?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may investigate the conduct of the city government and may make appraisals, comments, and recommendations to the Mayor on the efficiency, economy, and effectiveness of administrative practices, methods, systems, and controls.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_090","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recdJrN1x0JpYYo0n","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council subpoena witnesses as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc","recVGtbiaDBgMqTaG","rechiNVNlkL48X8Xv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_091","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recOQp0s4XOFs0KrX","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council administer oaths as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc","recgQvgd3Shu5a7uH","rechiNVNlkL48X8Xv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_092","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reckQWECybWld6rnp","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council compel testimony as necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc","rechiNVNlkL48X8Xv","recoLoeqCJnpr7eY9"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_093","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recsd9BbINgd62YMY","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council compel the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, and compel testimony, the production of books, papers, or other evidence necessary for the discharge of the duties of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc","rechiNVNlkL48X8Xv"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_094","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recUYXctOs38ObqhU","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How may Tulsa's City Council provide the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**By ordinance.** \n> The Council shall provide by ordinance the penalties for the contempt by any person who refuses to obey a Council order or subpoena.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","rec5ic94W9hDJJkfc"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_095","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recYZ5mRHw66YdYo2","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who designates the police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by Tulsa's City Council?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> The Mayor shall designate police officers to serve orders and subpoenas issued by the Council\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recgK36yEFw6QRuiJ","recVGtbiaDBgMqTaG","rechiNVNlkL48X8Xv","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_096","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 17 - Investigations and Hearings_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recP08q8Yh5pUYflk","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"May Tulsa's City Council delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The Council may delegate to the Mayor the authority to make rules, regulations, and orders necessary and proper to implement and administer ordinances.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_097","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 18 - Delegation of authority to make rules_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recERNwzNdC56lbWJ","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Barring investigations and hearings, through what avenues is it legal for Tulsa's City Council or individual councilors to communicate on matters of city business with the executive and administrative service?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"> ...soley through the Mayor, the heads of each division and department of the City, as well as such other persons as the Mayor shall delegate.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rech8ZnhQ6xMFXskv","recg4etkzkqLWNFtE","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recm6eIXpywCU4s9O","recgmxBwToQ2fMxpY","recgJkC22XaeUveje"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_098","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 19 - Interference with appointments or removals_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recZLx3m4Jn3HCenn","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Can City Councilors give orders to the Mayor's subordinates?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Barring the City Clerk and the City Attorney, no. \n> The Council and Councilors shall not give orders to any subordinate of the Mayor, either publicly or privately; provided, the prohibitions of this sentence shall not apply to the City Clerk and the City Attorney. Violation of this Section by any Councilor shall constitute willful maladministration and be sufficient grounds for removal from office as provided by the laws of Oklahoma. \nThe answer to this question is sourced from documentation concerning interference with appointments or removals.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recbMhrS5udASHOL1","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recm6eIXpywCU4s9O","recgmxBwToQ2fMxpY","recgJkC22XaeUveje"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_099","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 19 - Interference with appointments or removals_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recVwp6BMHzfQOJst","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How much money does a claim have to involve before the Mayor's approval and majority vote of the City Council is required?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["city council"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**$1 million.** \n> Where a claim is asserted against the City of Tulsa seeking to recover $1 million or more, prior to any settlement of such claim occurring, whether the total dollar amount claimed is comprised of a single claim or multiple claims arising out of a single act, accident, or the same transaction or occurrence, the settlement shall be approved by both the Mayor and by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recygMhYSJxEH8g89","recTL4r0Usb9BCNsJ","recrC4TQvJ11rDrQT","reccQujlrl8XzpgUR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_100","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 2, Section 19 - Interference with appointments or removals_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recWiAu4k37SJZBq0","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Are all executive powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_101","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.1. - Mayor_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"rec4UGgHpqFAD15ob","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Are all administrative powers of the City of Tulsa vested in the Mayor?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** \n> The executive and administrative powers of the City of Tulsa and any executive and administrative powers which may be conferred on the city by the Constitution or the laws of Oklahoma shall be vested in and exercised by the Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_102","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.1. - Mayor_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recyQKOg09pTdTh9h","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"What is the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**$105,000.** \n> The Mayor of the City of Tulsa, Oklahoma, shall receive as full compensation for his or her services as Mayor, effective with the term of office commencing April 1, 2002, at 2:00 p.m., an annual salary of One Hundred Five Thousand Dollars ($105,000.00), payable as employees of the City are paid.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","rec7UduLPBNpWCfHo","recygMhYSJxEH8g89"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_103","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Title 4 - Mayor, Auditor and Council. Article 1, Chapter 1, Section 100 - Salary of Mayor. From Ordinance No. 20190_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reczlfibbjwQ3S25D","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who determines the salary of Tulsa's Mayor?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["mayor-council relations"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**City Council.** \n> ...the salary to be received by the Mayor may be changed by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council; provided, no change in salary shall become effective prior to the commencement of the term of office next succeeding the term in which the change is made and then only in the event such change was approved prior to the general election for the next succeeding term.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_104","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.2. - Salary_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recDkMxHIZDdvB4DP","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who acts in the Mayor's absence?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Temporary Mayor.** \n> The Mayor shall file with the City Clerk, from time to time, a designation of one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor and perform the duties and exercise the powers of the Mayor during the absence or temporary disability of the Mayor or in the event of a vacancy in the office of the Mayor. The designation by the Mayor shall be subject to confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of the Council. Should the Mayor fail to file such designation, the Council shall designate one or more officers or employees of the city, other than members of the Council, who shall in the order specified act as Temporary Mayor.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recqckbuULaQhjRhV"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_105","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.3. - Absense, temporary disability, or vacancy_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recMXVVbs6EvfZ3Np","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is the chief executive of the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Mayor** of Tulsa. \n> The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_106","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recP6llSECTYD7S3S","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is the administrative officer for the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Mayor** of Tulsa. \n> The Mayor shall be the chief executive and administrative officer of the city...\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_107","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recSO8Zd9nXKsoz6s","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who has the authority to establish the City of Tulsa's policy priorities?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Mayor** of Tulsa, whose duty is to \n> ...identify the needs and establish the objectives and priorities of the city and make recommendations to the Council for meeting the needs and achieving the objectives.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_108","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection A_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recaYdpy5HJv6k7Fc","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who plans all boards, commissions, authorities, agencies, divisions, and departments of the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor","authorities, boards, & commissions"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec2NdYOcH1a9zvQX","recLOs35zYYLE35fI","recfJreUrwUrLyVJL","recYR0hYFlNEVOnX7","rec57K3gDdsswz8Qr","reckq8plKjAmo1oOR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_109","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection B_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recbENlHSBN2mY7PH","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa file plans for organizing the city's government for the following year?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to the City Charter, prior to May 1st.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","rec2NdYOcH1a9zvQX","recLOs35zYYLE35fI","recfJreUrwUrLyVJL","recYR0hYFlNEVOnX7","rec57K3gDdsswz8Qr","reckq8plKjAmo1oOR","recGZ2uhaRVhXOiMS"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_110","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection B_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recdREx7bAETStZ4b","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"Who prepares the City of Tulsa's budget?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor of Tulsa. However, per Article II Section 7.2., City Council can make changes to the budget.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_111","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection C_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recdU21R9YfvdK5T4","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"By what date must the Mayor of Tulsa submit the budget to City Council?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to the City Charter, it prior to May 1st. In 2022, the Mayor's budget presentation occured on April 20th. However, informal changes to municipal deadlines of any kind are not unusual.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_112","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection C_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recfUy3p3YrMprK0X","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"Are there tax-revenue streams in Tulsa that cannot be altered by the Mayor?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes,** the 2017 Public Sales Safety Tax. No revenue derived form this tax may ever be spent for any purpose other than public safety, as defined by Title 43-I.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_113","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection C_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"reciTexjhvBkkbOf4","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process","public finance"],"Question":"Is the Mayor required to expend the operating and capital budgets of the city?","Tags":["governance process","public finance"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["budget process"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes,** the Mayor of Tulsa is responsible for expending \n> ...as provided by law the funds of the city in accord with the adopted operating and capital budgets of the city.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_114","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection D_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process","revenue & spending"]},{"id":"recmIOjo0jIXMLMsS","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who is responsible for preserving the peace in the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Mayor.** The Mayor is to preserve the peace and enforce ordinances, rules, and regulations.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","rec9waV3GVmUG4v9L","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_115","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection E_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recmJrdJ56hD1070Z","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Who has the authority to appoint, supervise, and remove all officers and employees of the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**The Mayor.** Two exceptions to this are employees of the City Auditor and employees of City Council, who are appointed, supervised, and removed by each, respectively.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_116","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection F_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recplWQBzupVuhiw1","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"How are members of boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies appointed?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["the mayor","authorities, boards, & commissions"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Mayor appoints the members of all boards, commissions, authorities, and agencies, subject to the confirmation by a majority vote of the entire membership of City Council. All those appointed must be qualified electors and maintain residence within the city limits of the City of Tulsa.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec6lrWmFyJj2MfoK","recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recxdOAhjRYEtGBIR","recLOs35zYYLE35fI","recKFKtKkpyG5v4lT","rec2NdYOcH1a9zvQX","recYR0hYFlNEVOnX7"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_117","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection G_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"recsF6MDgTEEKZC3x","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Do members of authorities, boards, commissions, and agencies have to live in the city limits of the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["authorities, boards, & commissions"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.**\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec2NdYOcH1a9zvQX","recLOs35zYYLE35fI","recfJreUrwUrLyVJL","recYR0hYFlNEVOnX7","rectqNSvUt4brtYS2"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Code_118","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Code of Ordinances: Charter. Article 3, Section 1.4. - Executive and administrative powers and duties, Subsection G_\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]},{"id":"reczt6Hm5A1Kx9Ux2","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I register my neighborhood association with the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"To get your neighborhood association registered with the City of Tulsa, you will need to provide the name of the association, its boundaries (north, east, south, west), and primary contact information. This information must be provided on the Working in Neighborhoods' neighborhood association registration form. As of August 2022, this form can be found [here](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/government/departments/working-in-neighborhoods/neighborhoods/registration/). Alternatively, you may submit this information to us and we at Tulsa Policy Institute will be happy to file the form for you.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_001","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _City Website. Neighborhood Registration Form._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recOPQEfE3apeagD2","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What recommendations does the Tulsa Planning Office have for making an effective neighborhood association?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Establish leadership and defined roles while including all residents and encouraging volunteers. Further, establish structured meetings that allow for public input. Finally, seek to secure funding and establish partnerships with businesses and organizations. Please submit inquiry to us if your neighborhood association is interested in partnerning with the Tulsa Policy Institute.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recoS1cd55VZ046k2"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_002","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recsKttkmpMeNapAR","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Is joining a neighborhood association voluntary in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** Neighborhood associations cannot require your participation, unlike homeowner associations. Homeowner associations can compel your participation and adherence to rules, fines, and fees.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_003","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recFqk6yAVtx07Ggb","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"May anyone living within the boundaries of a neighborhood association join it?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes.** Membership is open to homeowners and tenants alike. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec5lKU0z4aujZLfa"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_004","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recy45EtuDTN1g5We","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Can neighborhood associations in Tulsa establish membership fees?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**Yes**, if they so choose.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec5lKU0z4aujZLfa","recKE790vQbaHmbeM"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_005","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recM8n8csurCdda7x","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What are the benefits of registering my neighborhood association with the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Through registering with the City of Tulsa, neighborhood associations can receive assistance with organizing** block parties**, receive **leadership trainings**, as well as participate in city programs such as **dumpster days** and the **neighborhood identity sign program**.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_006","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recHZT20iold95BRF","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What is the difference between a neighborhood association and a homeowner's association in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"A neighborhood association is a voluntary organization that is open to all homeowners and renters that inhabit the territory over which the organization is organized. These organizations lack the legal authority to levy liens or fees and they cannot compel residents to follow covenants. However, they can require membership dues. Homeowners associations are mandatory for all homeowners in the subdivision and are required to pay for services. These associations create policy in the form of covenants that all homeowners must follow. The homeowner association can levy fines, fees, and liens against a homeowner's property for refusal to follow the covenant. In the words of the Tulsa Planning Office, homeowner associations \"...act as a hyper-local form of government\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","rec4wpWPzMkrZUALU","rec45O4MPs95ap1wJ","rec3n5Csj65AI47CY","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_007","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 5._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recmFt4iIh8PQhmWW","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What is a Tulsa neighborhood identity sign and how can my neighborhood association have them implemented in our neighborhood?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Neighborhood signs are signs that are unique to each neighborhood, representing significant or historical features of the neighborhood. In order to see your sign implemented in your neighorbood, you must complete the following. First, your neighborhood association must submit a wrtitten proposal with a map of proposed sign locations to Traffic Operations, which will review and tentatively approve such locations. Second, you must develop a design for your sign (cannot have red text on white background, white text on red background, black text on yellow background, or black text on orange background). Third, you must submit your design to the Tulsa Planning Office to be added to the Arts Commission Agenda. Fourth, you must present your design at the Arts Commission meeting at which point the commission may offer suggestions or request changes to your design. Fifth, a sign manufacturer will make your signs according to your the city's specifications after which you will deliver your completed signs to the city. Finally, the city's Streets & Stormwater division will install your signs in the approved location.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recFyKRLU6h7jwQKQ","rec0sQtvGgcgXg7jH","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_008","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 7._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recp5SnTHLjr4XA3d","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I develop a neighborhood identity sign in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit, neighborhood associations recognized by the City of Tulsa can design welcome signs commemorating the historical or unique features of their slice of Tulsa. The process begins by submitting a written proposal and neighborhood map with proposed sign locations for tentative approval by the Traffic Operations Department. After that, your community can begin designing the sign according to certain specifications. Once its ready, submit the design to the Tulsa Planning Office. You'll have the opportunity to present your design to the Arts Commission, which may offer suggestions or request changes. After their approval, find a sign manufacturer and deliver your completed signs to the City of Tulsa. The Streets and Stormwater Department will install the signs at their designated locations. For more detailed information, review the toolkit. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recFyKRLU6h7jwQKQ","rec0sQtvGgcgXg7jH","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_009","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 7._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recF0vRein4FKuYAG","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I throw a block party in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit, neighborhood associations registered with the City can organize block parties in their community to bring neighbors closer together, celebrate, fundraise, or just have a good time. The only requirements are that the association notifies the City of when the party is scheduled, and that the association acquires barriers if the party is using a public street. Beyond that, the tookit recommends some common sense steps like checking the weather forecast, scheduling a rain date, organizing a party planning committee, and coordinate on who will provide which activities/food. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","reco1OdEL91D6SdZx","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recOv5VE6tdQiwyPA"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_010","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 8._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recjC9hwVLu8yJE23","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I organize a neighborhood cleanup in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"According to Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit, registered neighborhood associations can get help from the City to beautify their community through a neighborhood cleanup. cleanup project could include, picking up litter, clearing sidewalks, planting, or helping a neighbor with a necessary home renovation. The City will even provide a 30-yard dumpster for free, just fill out a request here. During the summer months, associations could be eligible for additional free supplies through the Great American Cleanup sponsored by the Oklahoma affiliate of Keep America beautiful. Find out about additional resources in the Neighborhood Toolkit\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recELqo4B4ZEocOqI","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_011","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Pages 9-10._\n\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recdJyCbuHpkXOHLu","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I report code violations in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["report or request"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa has several ordinances, or codes, which apply to how property owners must maintain their property. The Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit has a helpful list of common violations including tall grass, and debris in the yard. Before taking action against a neighbor regarding a potential violation, it's worth reviewing municipal codes and the bylaws of your Homeowners Association (if you belong to one) in order to determine which policies apply. If you suspect a violation of municipal code, you can report it by calling 3-1-1, visiting [tulsa311.com](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/home), or through the Tulsa311 mobile app. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recRJBtqeF69Iewhi","reckyRUNzxZWiOrnz","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_012","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Pages 11-12._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recIXjskCTgB35RHJ","Tags_PreOctober":["law & justice"],"Question":"Can my neighbor keep their inoperable vehicle in their front yard?","Tags":["law & justice"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["vehicles"],"Public":true,"Answer":"**No**, according to the Tulsa Zoning Code Section 45.140. The Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit states \"Inoperable vehicles must be stored in a fully enclosed structure\"(11), the Tulsa Zoning Codes states that inoperable vehicles may be placed in the back yard. Further, note that a vehicle is not inoperable merely because it \"...does not include a motor vehicle that has been rendered temporarily incapable of being driven under its own motor power, solely to perform ordinary service or repair operations\"(Section 95.120). A vehicle is only inoperable if, for a seven day period, the vehicle's engine, wheels, or other parts are removed OR in which the engine, wheels, or other parts have been damaged, altered, or modified such that the vehicle is not capable of being driven.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recRJBtqeF69Iewhi","reckyRUNzxZWiOrnz","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","rec8Qwg6mbkoE66Rx","recLbp4zqgMf7Kk0v"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_013","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["policies & regulations"],"Source":"City of Tulsa._ Tulsa Zoning Code: Section 45.140 & 95.120. _\nTulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 11._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["policies & regulations"]},{"id":"recprRZEmaiFQcIZc","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I establish a neighborhood tool library in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Starting a community tool library in your Tulsa neighborhood is relatively straightforward and, unlike some other community initiatives, doesn't require any approvals from the City. An informal tool library can simply be verbal agreements between neighbors. Resources like digital spreadsheets, social media groups, and free online platforms can help your neighborhood support a more complex tool library with multiple participants. [Sharestarter](http://sharestarter.org) has helpful guides on how to setup a robust tool library, and online lending platforms like [Myturn](https://myturn.com/) can help you manage loans and returns. Visit the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit for more tips.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recMyNAFpsmFFQR6h","recNUVECzOhYh6dnX","recGuE0gbK9WuV26W","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_014","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 13._\n"},{"id":"rec8aGzJTsY9GTzMN","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What is an alert neighbors program?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"An Alert Neighbors program is a framework for members of a community to organize around protecting the safety of themselves and their neighbors through education, vigilance and cooperation. The foundation of an alert neighbors program is building familiarity with your neighbors through communication and observation, to be able to spot suspicious activity if/when it occurs. A well-functioning program will hold meetings, organize educational presentations from public safety officials, and centralize important communications through a social media group or contact list. For more tips, review the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recVOu4S7qEpwiFz9","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_015","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 14._\n"},{"id":"recQ6ib28eweg2yaC","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I start an alert neighbors program in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"An Alert Neighbors program is an entirely grassroots organization. Step one is to discuss the idea with neighbors and identify somebody who has the time and dedication to serve as program coordinator for your neighborhood. The coordinator(s) will establish a meeting schedule, invite speakers to give presentations, establish social media or other communications methods, recruit block captains, and organize training. Block captains help manage communications within a single block or apartment building. Simply participating in an Alert Neighbors program and becoming more familiar with your neighbors will go a long way in building trust in your community and learning to identify unusual or suspicious activity in your neighborhood. For more tips about organizing and growing an Alert Neighbors program, review the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recVOu4S7qEpwiFz9","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_016","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 14._\n"},{"id":"recb2mqOhYvTzuBtm","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I prepare for an emergency in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Natural disasters, especially in Tulsa, can pose a significant risk to life and property. Each type of disaster can pose unique challenges, but a few proactive steps can put you in a better spot for any disaster. For instance, having a plan ahead of time about when to leave your home, where to go, and how to maintain contact with loved ones can save significant decision time when disaster strikes. Having a go-bag, or emergency kit, packed with essentials also reduces the risk of being unprepared if you have to leave. If you have the time and resources, modifications to boost your home's resiliency are often worth the expense. [Tulsa 311](https://tulsa311.com/site/wss/redirect/1000450) also offers a service where residents can inquiry about the risk of flooding at their residence. For in-depth tips and guides to disaster planning, visit [American Red Cross](http://redcross.org) and [Ready](http://ready.gov).\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSlLVBIMDqqcsOz","rec1SXJLS1PrTbAXE","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_017","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 15._\n"},{"id":"recD7qV5csbm3Afgh","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I install a storm shelter in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Storm shelters and safe rooms are the best ways to keep you and your family safe from a tornado. But they can be expensive, frequently costing between $2,500 and $8,000.  In Oklahoma, there are options to help you finance a storm shelter on your property. The State of Oklahoma offers rebates granted by lottery through the [Sooner Safe](https://www.ok.gov/OEM/saferoom/app/) program.  Storm shelter loans are available at many local credit unions and FHA loans can be used to install a safe room in your home. Regardless of how it's financed, shelters or safe rooms should be installed by reputable and insured companies. Shelters built to FEMA standards are designed to withstand winds from an E-5 tornado. Once installed, [register](https://survey123.arcgis.com/share/4e885823f3b846d59906f183c428b642) your new shelter or safe room with the City of Tulsa so first responders can find you. Review the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit for more tips on disaster preparedness and installing storm sheltering.\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","rec8t9nmRIbtvxP1x","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_018","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 16._\n"},{"id":"recKurmkfCL7WXRMH","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I plant and care for trees in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Planting a tree is a deceptively significant decision that requires some careful planning to avoid serious challenges as the tree matures. Those who wish to plant a tree on their property must account for the tree's suitability to the climate, the risk of root systems damaging foundations or utilities, the risk of top-growth damaging power lines, the tree's ability to withstand severe weather, and how they'll care for the tree in the long-term. If you want to plant a tree within 12 feet of the curb, you'll need a permit and a License Agreement from the City of Tulsa. Before buying a tree, visit [Tulsa Master Gardeners](http://tulsamastergardeners.org) to find out which trees thrive in Tulsa. Before planting, regardless of location, call 8-1-1 or visit [Okie811](http://okie811.org) to have utility workers mark the location of buried utility lines that must be avoided. Review the Tulsa Planning Office's Neighborhood Toolkit for more info and resources about trees. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recfh81PIpJDqjzMH","recdZj59grW6AoCkH","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_019","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 17._\n"},{"id":"recRtAR1YVxpadQyh","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I install rain barrels in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"You'll want to place your barrel near an existing downspout from your gutters, and elevate the barrel on a steady base for gravity to help water run through your hose. Empty and clean the barrel at the end of summer to prevent freezing damage. At some points in time, the City of Tulsa partners with a business to offer discounted rain barrels. Follow City of Tulsa social media channels to find out when discounts are available. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recuSesYtVg40gW5d","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_020","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 19._\n"},{"id":"rec9gnsbyLJA9OXN5","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I plant a rain garden in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Rain gardens can both enhance the beauty of your yard and contribute to flood mitigation by absorbing rainwater that would otherwise become storm water runoff. The best spot for a rain garden is the lowest point in your yard, where rainwater flows naturally. To determine the size of your garden, multiply the square footage of hard surfaces (roof, patio, sidewalk) on your property by 5-10%. Keep in mind that not all of those hard surfaces may direct rain water to your garden. Once your garden is situated, dig out a six to eight inch deep depression for maximum absorption. The key factor for a rain garden is the rate at which water infiltrates the soil. If you find that the soil is hard-packed or doesn't drain well, it's worth picking a different spot or digging deeper to amend the soil with sand. When its time to plant, choose native varieties to attract pollinators, specifically ones that can tolerate wet roots for a day or two.  The OSU extension office has a helpful plant selection guide [here.](https://extension.okstate.edu/fact-sheets/sustainable-landscapes-designing-a-rain-garden-for-residential-property.html)\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recDNE4Khu45LY42t","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_021","Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 20._\n"},{"id":"recd73crvkSwsZu19","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I request mixed-use zoning along BRT Route?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development","zoning"],"Public":true,"Answer":"If you own property within a half-mile of a Bus Rapid Transit station on Peoria Ave. in Tulsa, your property may be eligible for re-zoning as a mixed-use district. Mixed-use zoning allows you to develop or redevelop your property to support any combination of residential, retail, and/or office space. The Tulsa Planning Office has a map and staff to help you find out if your property is eligible. If it is, you can submit an application for free (instead of the standard $2,000 cost) until Dec 31, 2023. Staff at the Tulsa Metropolitan Planning Commission will review your application and notify neighbors of their opportunity to comment on the application. TMAPC staff will recommend approval or denial of your application at a public meeting. If recommended for approval, your case will then appear before Tulsa City council for a final vote on approval. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recgdKPlaYC1v6B5Z","recUV4OXFuslnxwJP","rec6l9YWOd4MXGsTr","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_022","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 22._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recAPXs5A94TmKxCN","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I get a free dumpster to use for my neighborhood cleanup?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["neighborhood development"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Neighborhood associations which are registered with the City of Tulsa can request a free 30 yard dumpster, dropped off and picked up by the City. The City of Tulsa's Neighborhood Dumpster Program is a service available to registered neighborhood associations to perform neighborhood clean-up activities. Participating groups can make use of 30-yard containers to dispose of eligible household items twice a year. _Please note: During inclement weather, employees assigned to the Neighborhood Dumpster Program will be reassigned to work the weather event. In this case, your drop-off/pick-up dates may be adjusted._\n\nDumpster Use Rules:\n1. Dumpsters are for use at residential sites and **CANNOT** be used for commercial purposes (for example, to clean out rental properties).\n2. Use Restrictions: Some items are not permitted to be put into City of Tulsa dumpsters. Examples include limbs, grass clippings, Freon bearing appliance (such as refrigerators), and roofing materials. \n3. Dumpsters are not designed to be more than 3/4ths full and items are not permitted to be placed on the ground around the dumpster.\n4. Neighborhood Associations can request up to two dumpsters per year.\n\nApply [Here](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/government/departments/working-in-neighborhoods/neighborhoods/dumpster-program/dumpster-request-for-neighborhood-cleanups/) to Request your Dumpster!\n\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recJxDjSSZ5eRk109","recKwdNep7HvUUvgc","recELqo4B4ZEocOqI","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_023","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 9. _\nCity of Tulsa. _City Website. Dumpster Program._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"rec6LRo20sasivYGs","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How can I safely dispose of hazardous household chemicals/materials in Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Tulsa's Household Pollutant Collection Facility accepts many items not allowed in regular trash pickup, including lawn chemicals, paints, fluorescent lights, and more. \nTulsa residents can drop-off for **free** by showing a drivers license or City of Tulsa utility bill.\n \n**Acceptable Items**\n- Aerosols\n- Automotive Fluids\n- Cooking Oil/Grease\n- Flammable Liquids\n- Fluorescent and CFL Light bulbs\n- Household and Car Batteries\n- Household Cleaners\n- Latex Paint\n- Lawn Chemicals\n- Mercury Thermostats\n- Oil-Based Paints and Paint Thinner\n- Pool Chemicals\n- Small Electronics\n \n**Not Acceptable Items**\n- Ammunition/Explosives\n- Asbestos\n- Industrial or Commercially Generated Waste (including NHIW waste)\n- Large Electronics (TV's, Monitors, Computers)\n- [Medical](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/government/departments/water-and-sewer/wastewater/wastewater-pollution-prevention/medication-disposal/) or Biomedical Waste Food or Organic Waste\n- Radioactive Material\n- Tires\n- Unknown Materials or Substances \n\n_To find out where to dispose of items that are not accepted by the Household Pollutant Collection Facility, click [here.](https://www.cityoftulsa.org/government/departments/streets-and-stormwater/household-pollutant-collection-facility/disposal-of-non-accepted-items/)_ \n \n**Don't live in the City of Tulsa? No problem.** \n\nIf you live outside of City Limits, but still inside of Tulsa County, you can obtain a voucher from the Metropolitan Environmental Trust to drop off the first 45 pounds of pollutants for free. After this, it costs $1.33 per pound and can be paid with Mastercard or Visa. Call 918.584.0584 to obtain the voucher that is required prior to dropping off your pollutants.\n \n**Household Pollutant Collection Facility Hours of Operation:**\n\nWednesday and Saturday: \n8AM - 11:30AM & 12PM - 4:30PM\n  \n4502 S. Galveston Ave. | Tulsa, OK 74107. 918.591.4325. \n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","reck1kwu0Ax8s2U3s","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_024","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _City Website. Household Pollutant Collection Facility._\nTulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 10._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recM1UFoS5OrSPXXt","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"Where can I dispose of fallen limbs, leaves, or other green waste in Tulsa for free?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["recycling & waste"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa offers **free** yard waste drop-off. \n\n**Drop-off Location**\n2100 N. 145th Ave.\nDrop-off available 7:30AM to 5PM daily, except City holidays.\n\n**What Can You Dispose Here?**\nResidents may dispose of grass, leaves, brush and tree limbs. \n\n**What Will You Need to Bring?**\nA current drivers license with a Tulsa address or a City of Tulsa utility bill.\n\nWood chips are available for free, as well!\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSaB0ugjsBczpUQ","rechGKl53YLEWSFKy","recws8bLQ6cyFvH6B","reck1kwu0Ax8s2U3s","recBTeDboTe5vDD9l","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Planning_025","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"Tulsa Planning Office. _Neighborhood Toolkit. Page 10._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recBeu2kRrxU0TKQm","Tags_PreOctober":["governance process"],"Question":"Why is there a road closure in Tulsa?","Tags":["governance process"],"Concepts":["public service"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The City of Tulsa offers a live traffic map that displays road closures around the city, also providing an explanation of the cause of the closure. Where closure is due to construction, the contractor and price is also displayed. This tool can be  found [here](https://cityoftulsa.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=0910c978896e423e8f4f826953b83b48).\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recmM3m7G1ByTAI1T","recSlK0QKzpjweE7g","recdoCgCxV6RbWD0L","recyJCadYKnbBRD0a"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Tools_01","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Traffic Flow Map_. \n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recr3fqVsuIhbUaai","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"What classes are offered by the City of Tulsa?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["take a class"],"Public":true,"Answer":"The Parks, Culture, & Recreation Department offers a variety of classes and programs, as can be seen [here](https://guide.tulsaparks.org/CourseActivities.aspx?id=22&cat=8).  Most of these are listed below.\n\nFor most courses, the associated costs include each class session, which vary by program. For example, most fitness classes include 8-13 sessions.\n\n**Educational**\n- English Classes (All ages. $0)\n- Junior Naturalist Program (Ages 8-12. $100)\n- Kids Programs (Ages 1-8. $0-135)\n- United Health Care Open [Medicare] Enrollment (Ages 65+. $0)\n\n**Fitness**\n- Low-Impact Aerobics (Ages 18+. $25 for residents. $31 for non-residents)\n- Senior X-R-Cise (Ages 16+. $35 for residents. $44 for non-residents)\n- Self-Defense and Fitness (Ages 18+. $25 for residents. $31 for non-residents)\n- Ladies Private Weight Training (Ages 18-99. $2 for residents. $0 for non-residents)\n- Small Group Weight Training (Ages 16-65. $15)\n- Balancing Exercises (Ages 55-100. $0)\n- 30 Minute Workout (Ages 9-99. $2)\n- Family Dance & Exercise (Ages 5-99. $5)\n- Refit Revolution (Ages 13+. $25)\n- Strong Nation (Cardio + HIIT) (Ages 13-99. $25)\n- H.I.I.T (High Intensity Interval Train) (Ages 16-99. $25)\n- Zumba (Ages 16+. $35 for residents. $44 for non-residents)\n- Zumba with Sarah (Ages 16+. $30 for residents. $37 for non-residents)\n- Classics Morning Walk (All ages. $0)\n- Walk and Talk (Ages 18-99. $0)\n\n**Sports & Athletics**\n\n_Basketball, Soccer, Volleyball, Tennis, & Pickleball_\n- 40+ Basketball (Ages 40-99. $0)\n- Youth Soccer (Ages 7-9 or 9-12. $75 for residents. $91 for non-residents).\n- Volleyball Developmental Program (Grades 4-5 or 6-8. $50 for residents or $62 for non-residents)\n- Open Adult Volleyball (All ages. $0)\n- Open Pickleball (Ages 18+. $0)\n\n_Archery_\n- Archery (Ages 8-80. $20 for residents. $25 for non-residents)\n\n_Martial Arts_\n- Tae Kwon Do (Ages 5-100. $25 for residents. 31$ for non-residents)\n- Shotokan (Ages 9+. $25 for residents. 31$ for non-residents)\n- Karate (Ages 5-11 or 12-17. $5 for residents. 0$ for non-residents)\n- Young Samurai Martial Arts (Ages 6-14. $35 for residents. $45 for non-residents)\n- Close Combat Martial Arts (Ages 15-95. $50)\n- Weapons Martial Arts (Ages 15-95. $60)\n- Light Saber Martial Arts (Ages 8-95 or 99. $20 for residents. $25 for non-residents)\n\n_Gymnastics_\n- Tiny Tumbling (Ages 3-6. $40 for residents. $50 for non-residents)\n- Beginner Tumbling (Ages 6-18. $40 for residents. $50 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Little Kinder Kids (Ages 2-4. $40 for residents. $50 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Kinder Kids (Ages 4-6. $40 for residents. $50 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics Kinderplus (Ages 3-5. $45 for residents. 54$ for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Jam & Slam (Ages 6-18. $40 for residents. $50 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Girls Pre Team (Ages 5-17 or 18. $75 for residents. $90 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Boys Pre Team (Ages 6-18. $50 or $85 for residents. $60 or $105 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics Team Level 1, 3, & 4 (Ages5-18)\n    - Level 1: $85 for residents. $105 for non-residents.\n    - Level 3: $95 for residents. $120 for non-residents.\n    - Level 4: $115 for residents. $140 for non-residents.\n- Gymnastics - Beginner (Ages 6-8 or 12. $45 for residents. $54 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Pre-Team (Ages 9-12. $45 for residents. $54 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Beginner/Homeschool (Ages 6-14. $45 for residents. $54 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Junior Beginner (Ages 4-6. $45 for residents. $54 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics - Intermediate (Ages 8-12. $45 for residents. $54 for non-residents)\n- Gymnastics Team - Twisters (Ages 4-15. $90)\n\n**Visual Arts**\n\n_Ceramics, Clay, & Pottery_\n- Ceramics (Ages 18+. $5)\n- Beginning Pottery Wheel (Ages 16+. $140)\n- Intermediate Pottery Wheel (Ages 16+. $115)\n- Make a Mask: A Clay Date for Couples (Ages 16+. $75)\n- The Art of Raku (Ages 16+. $130)\n- Small Sculptures Workshop (Ages 16+. $90)\n- Gone Fishin' Parent-Child Clay Workshop (Ages 7+. $45)\n\n_Drawing & Painting_\n- Portrait Painters (Ages 18+. $0)\n- Landscapes from the Land of Enchantment (Ages 16+. $45 for residents. $56 for non-residents)\n- Linoleum Block Print Notecards (Ages 16+. $45 for residents. $65 for non-residents)\n- Waxing Poetic Basic Worskhop: Cold Wax Painting (Ages 16+. $60. $75 for non-residents)\n- Composition, Color, & Design Workshop(Ages 16+. $65 for residents. $81 for non-residents)\n- Making Your Mark: An Intro to Pastel Workshop (Ages 16+. $35 for residents. $44 for non-residents)\n- Collage Sketchbooks Workshop (Ages 16+. $60 for residents. $81 for non-residents)\n- Capturing Light & Shadow in Pastel (Ages 16+. $65 for residents. $81 for non-residents)\n- Introduction to Drawing (Ages 10+. $65 for residents. $81 for non-residents)\n\n_Metals, Jewelry, & Fiber Arts_\n- Jewelry 101 (Ages 16+. $150 for residents. $188 for non-residents)\n- Make Your Own Bolo Tie (Ages 16+. $100 for residents. $125 for non-residents)\n- Make a Copper Belt Buckle (Ages 16+. $70 for residents. $88 for non-residents)\n- Soldering Crash Course (Ages 16+. $55 for residents. $69 for non-residents)\n\n**Performing Arts**\n- Ballet & Jazz (Ages 6-15. $25 for residents. $31 for non-residents)\n- Adult Body Discovery & Technique (Ages 18-99. $0)\n- Beginning Dance Techniques (Ages 3-9. $0)\n- Lacy Jammers (Ages 5-15. $0)\n- Older and Bolder Dance Group (Ages 55-100. $100)\n- Accordion Band (All ages, $0)\n\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recRQKSOc1jkTigGe","recruTp47STFgwlIB"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Samuel_Tools_02","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["public services"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Tulsa Parks Course Activities provided by the Parks, Culture, & Recreation Department._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["public services"]},{"id":"recBHG04HEVgMAPNw","Tags_PreOctober":["accessing tulsa"],"Question":"How do I speak in front of Tulsa City Council?","Tags":["accessing tulsa"],"Contributor":"Samuel","Concepts":["participate"],"Public":true,"Answer":"Speaking to City Council is most optimally conducted by speaking at their Regular Meetings, currently scheduled to occur on (most) Wednesdays. To be brief, you can show up at regular meetings and sign up to speak when you get there unless you wish to speak on an item that is not on the agenda. In that case, you should submit this [form](https://www.tulsacouncil.org/media/16442/tulsa_council_public_comment_form.pdf) to [secretary@tulsacouncil.org](mailto:secretary@tulsacouncil.org) before 12:00pm on the Thursday prior to the meeting at which you wish to speak. \nBelow is a guide to aid you in this process.\n\n**Speaking on Agenda Items**\nTo speak on a specific agenda item at Tulsa City Council's regular meetings, you must sign a \"Request to Speak\" form in-person at the meeting at which you intend to speak. When signing this form, you must state the following.\n- Your name.\n- Your address.\n- Whether you support or oppose the specific agenda item.\n_This will be recorded and televised on the City of Tulsa's government access channel [TGOV](https://tulsa-ok.granicus.com/ViewPublisher.php?view_id=4)._\n\n**Speaking on an Issue of Your Choice**\nWith more preparation you may also speak to City Council \"on any item affecting the City of Tulsa\". Such speech is classified by the City of Tulsa as \"Public Comments\". Such comments usually take place at the end of meetings and are not televised. In order to participate in public comment, follow the following steps.\n- Fill out this [form](https://www.tulsacouncil.org/media/16442/tulsa_council_public_comment_form.pdf).\n- After filling out the section titled \"Topic\", add to this section that you found this form through the Tulsa Policy Institute.\n- Submit this form to the Secretary of the Council either in writing, by fax, or email: secretary@tulsacouncil.org.\n\n**_You must submit this form no later than noon on the Thursday prior to the meeting you wish to speak at. To check if your name has been added to the agenda minutes, see [here.](https://www.tulsacouncil.org/apps/TulsaCouncilArchive)_**\n\n**Guidelines and Restrictions on Public Comment**\n- Citizens are limited to two \"Public Comment\" items each meeting. A citizen is not permitted to res-submit a request on the same subject within 180 days from the preceding request.\n- No action is taken on matters raised or discussed during \"Public Comments\" with one exception: \"possibly placing such matters on a future regular meeting or standing committee meeting of the Council\".\n- The topic should be specific, but brief. City Council suggests using words that \"an ordinary individual may understand what the topic is about\". Language submitted by citizens \"will be reviewed and, if necessary, revised to ensure compliance with the Oklahoma Open Meeting Act\".\n- Public Comments are intended to provide citizens opportunities to inform City Council about new issues affecting Tulsa. It is not a Q&A session.\n\n**Need to Know Before Attending City Council Meetings**\n- No weapon, including pocket knives, are permitted at public meetings.\n- Persons who require special accommodations to participate in City Council Meetings should contact Lori Doring through one of the following means.\n    - **Mail:** 175 East Second Street, Fourth Floor, Tulsa, Oklahoma\n    - **Phone:** 918-596-1990\n    - **Email:** [loridoring@tulsacouncil.org](mailto:loridoring@tulsacouncil.org)\n- \"Persons using a TDD may contact OKLAHOMA RELAY at 1-800-722-0353 and voice calls should be made to 1-800-522-8506 to communicate via telephone with hearing telephone users and vice versa\".\n","Concepts_PreOctober":["recX9nNDKs0rtBi3g","recTduFwT9ATeQB7t","recjQZSeuGijmUfoF","recZGgJu72BM3szBu"],"Author":"Samuel","QA Code":"Sub_Samuel_01","Tags_PreOctober copy copy":["city gov & policy process"],"Source":"City of Tulsa. _Website. Meetings._\nCity of Tulsa. _Website. Submit a Public Comment._\n","Tags_PreOctober copy":["city gov & policy process"]}]